<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Boston on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://yentran.org/tags/boston/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Boston on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yentran.org/tags/boston/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hub on Wheels 2010</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-07-10-hub-on-wheels-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-07-10-hub-on-wheels-2010/</guid>
      <description>Every September since 2005, the city of Boston has held a charity bike ride to benefit of one of its educational programs. The event is called Hub on Wheels, a clever pun based on Boston&amp;rsquo;s modest nickname for itself, the Hub of the Universe. For the majority of riders, it would be the only time of the year that they get an intimate view of some of Boston&amp;rsquo;s lesser-known neighborhoods. There are 3 available courses, 10-, 30- and 50-mile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Bruins Stanley Cup Parade</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</guid>
      <description>Boston&amp;rsquo;s first Stanley Cup parade in 39 years was going to take place on Saturday, June 18, three days after the team celebrated on the ice in Vancouver. It was as definitive a &amp;ldquo;clear your calendar&amp;rdquo;-type event as it will ever be. On the morning of C-day, we got up early, loaded up with a hearty breakfast, filled the caffeine meter, and made sure we went to the bathroom before heading down to the T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We want the Cup!</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-14-we-want-the-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-14-we-want-the-cup/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the eve before the biggest game in my history as a Bruins fan. I&amp;rsquo;m so nervous I&amp;rsquo;m going to have problem going to sleep. I had known about hockey quite early on since Las Vegas had a minor-league team, the now-defunct Las Vegas Thunder, and a friend was a big fan. Despite knowing so little about the game, I was hooked immediately when I came to Boston in the mid-90s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The man they call Bobby</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-09-the-man-they-call-bobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-09-the-man-they-call-bobby/</guid>
      <description>TD Bank Garden, Boston on June 8, around 19:00. It was moments before Game 4 of the Stanley Cup finals between the Boston Bruins and the Vancouver Canucks. In the darkened arena, packed to the rafters with almost 18000 screaming fans, the lone spotlight descended on an area in the stands. Momentarily, a middle-aged man clad in a vintage Bruins jersey stepped into the light. The crowd erupted. It was none other than the legendary Bobby Orr, the man universally regarded as the finest defenseman in the history of hockey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
