<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pc on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://yentran.org/tags/pc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pc on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yentran.org/tags/pc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Windows Media Center No Tuner Available Error With HDHomeRun Prime</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2013-11-02-fixing-windows-media-center-no-tuner-available-error-with-hdhomerun-prime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2013-11-02-fixing-windows-media-center-no-tuner-available-error-with-hdhomerun-prime/</guid>
      <description>I have the HDHomeRun Prime network tuner. Recently, after a Verizon FiOS tech rebooted the ONT to fix a network issue, I got the dreaded Viewing or Listening Conflict. No tuner available to satisfy the current request error when trying to view Live TV in Windows Media Center. When I tried Settings &amp;gt; Windows Media Center setup, I got the error:
 Tuner Not found. The TV signal cannot be configured because a TV tuner was not detected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Wifi for the Brother HL-2280DW Laser Printer on Windows</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-02-09-configuring-wifi-for-the-brother-hl-2280dw-laser-printer-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-02-09-configuring-wifi-for-the-brother-hl-2280dw-laser-printer-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>With laser printer, scanner, Ethernet and Wifi interface rolled into one, the Brother HL-2280DW is quite a little champ. However, for me, getting the Wifi to work was a bit of a challenge. The installer would die silently after configuring Wifi but without having installed the software. After some trial and error, I was able to successfully install for Ethernet . With the software installed, I was able to configure Wifi afterward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing antivirus program changes FireFox keyword URL</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-01-03-installing-antivirus-changes-firefox-keyword-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-01-03-installing-antivirus-changes-firefox-keyword-url/</guid>
      <description>I tried out a well-known cloud-based antivirus solution. It worked well enough, but after I installed it, I noticed that my FireFox searches were now redirected from Google to Yahoo!. In the FF config screen (which can be opened by typing &amp;ldquo;about:config&amp;rdquo; in the location bar), I noticed that the keyword.URL setting had been changed to Yahoo!:
This setting dictates which search service is used when the user enters a keyword (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to grant permissions to the Application Pool Identity for IIS 7.5</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-09-06-granting-permissions-to-the-application-pool-identity-in-iis-7-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-09-06-granting-permissions-to-the-application-pool-identity-in-iis-7-5/</guid>
      <description>Up to IIS 7 (Windows Vista and Windows Server 2008), the default app pool identity is NetworkService 7. In IIS 7.5 (Windows 7 and Windows Server 2008 R2) the app pool identity is changed to something called ApplicationPoolIdentity.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you set up a virtual directory or application that uses this app pool. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to grant access permission on the physical path to ApplicationPoolIdentity. However, you&amp;rsquo;d find that there is no such user account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing malware</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-08-23-removing-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-08-23-removing-malware/</guid>
      <description>My computer got a dose of malware today. The trojan got a hold of my USB drive. It made all of my files and folders hidden, then injected executables with the same names. It also hid the .exe extension so that the executables appeared in place of the legitimate objects they were masquerading. It gave the fake folders the right icon so that they looked just like folders. The objective is to fool the user into double-clicking the folders to open them but instead executing the trojan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Windows 7 for the ASRock 939Dual-SATA2 motherboard</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-08-14-installing-windows-7-x86-for-the-asrock-939dual-sata2-motherboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-08-14-installing-windows-7-x86-for-the-asrock-939dual-sata2-motherboard/</guid>
      <description>The ASRock 939Dual-SATA2 motherboard is a little long in the tooth but still quite capable. Mine has been running Windows XP Media Center Edition for some time and I decided to upgrade it to Windows 7. The challenge is that the motherboard&amp;rsquo;s JMicron SATA2 chipset isn&amp;rsquo;t detected automatically at installation. If you want to install Windows on a SATA hard drive, you will have to load the driver first. The other problem is that, as of the time of writing, there is no Windows 7 driver for the ULi integrated Ethernet controller due to the age of the hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
