<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hockey on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://yentran.org/categories/hockey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hockey on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yentran.org/categories/hockey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sports I would watch</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2014-02-07-sports-i-would-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2014-02-07-sports-i-would-watch/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;if I had an unlimited amount of free time, bathroom breaks and no desire to have a life.
 Olympic men&amp;rsquo;s hockey Bruins hockey NHL hockey IIHF tournament hockey such as the World Juniors Top-flight European professional hockey (KHL, Swedish Elite League, Finnish Elite League) Olympic women&amp;rsquo;s hockey. It&amp;rsquo;s enjoyable but less exciting than the men&amp;rsquo;s game due to the lack of strong competition; basically it&amp;rsquo;s a 2-horse race between Canada and USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruins took down Sabres in costly victory</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2013-10-23-bruins-took-down-sabres-in-costly-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2013-10-23-bruins-took-down-sabres-in-costly-victory/</guid>
      <description>It was game 1 of the World Series. Yawn. Since our pickup game was canceled in part due to the aforementioned sport&amp;ndash;eh recreational&amp;ndash;event, it was going to be either a work night or an early night. Fortunately, the Bruins came to the rescue by taking on the Sabres. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing it was on NBCSports/Versus instead of NESN, where viewers would have been bombarded with a constant barrage of WS updates, even though the network TV announcers are downright annoying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruins Training Camp 2013</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2013-09-17-bruins-training-camp-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2013-09-17-bruins-training-camp-2013/</guid>
      <description>Having moved to the &amp;lsquo;burbs recently, I look forward to attending the Bruins&amp;rsquo; regular-season practice sessions at Ristuccia Arena in Wilmington, now that it&amp;rsquo;s only a few miles away. The 2013 Training Camp, though, was held at TD Garden the weekend of September 14-15. Of course I was going to be there.
The 2013 season was a bit of a roller coaster ride. It was thrilling at times, but ultimately disappointing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You played with who?</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2013-03-08-you-played-with-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2013-03-08-you-played-with-who/</guid>
      <description>Since 1999 I&amp;rsquo;ve helped run a pickup hockey group at the Skating Club of Boston. We&amp;rsquo;re really not crazy about the rink there. The ice is intended for figure skaters so it&amp;rsquo;s soft and thus slow and quick to become choppy. There is no glass above the boards so if you shoot high enough you&amp;rsquo;d have to go fish for the puck under the stands. And since figure skaters generally stay in the middle of the ice, the edges are neglected and not well maintained; this is a problem if you try to &amp;ldquo;wrap the puck around the board&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Bruins&#39; 2011 White House appearance</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-01-23-on-the-bruins-2011-white-house-appearance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-01-23-on-the-bruins-2011-white-house-appearance/</guid>
      <description>Today the Bruins appeared at the White House where President Obama greeted them and honored their accomplishments as 2011 Stanley Cup champions. Included in the group photo were Americans, Canadians, Czechs, a Slovak, a Finn, and a German. Notable in his absence was Bruins goalie Tim Thomas, Stanley Cup playoffs MVP, winner of multiple awards and the only American player who made significant contribution to the team&amp;rsquo;s Cup run. The details of Thomas&#39; absence are covered elsewhere, but it has become clear that it is politically motivated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are the 2011 Bruins?</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-23-who-are-the-bruins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-23-who-are-the-bruins/</guid>
      <description>Defensemen #33 Zdeno Chara - Tallest man in hockey history and probably using the longest stick and wearing the largest skates as well. With his monstrous wingspan he can easily cover his half of the ice. Very nice guy off the ice, but a big (and tall) bogeyman on it.
#44 Dennis Seidenberg - Rugged German-born defenseman. Blocks a ton of shot. Possesses outstanding balance and is very strong on his skates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 reasons why hockey is the best</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-21-why-hockey-is-the-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-21-why-hockey-is-the-best/</guid>
      <description>Would you expect any less from a die-hard hockey fan? So with a warning that this is going to be shamelessly biased, here goes.
 At the 2011 NHL All-Stars game, NY Islanders forward Michael Grabner won the Fastest Skater competition with a time of 14.238 seconds. The track length is about 550 ft. This translates to 38.6 ft or 12.9 yards/second. For comparison, let&amp;rsquo;s look at the fastest 40-yard dash for football players, who are speedsters in their own right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Bruins Stanley Cup Parade</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</guid>
      <description>Boston&amp;rsquo;s first Stanley Cup parade in 39 years was going to take place on Saturday, June 18, three days after the team celebrated on the ice in Vancouver. It was as definitive a &amp;ldquo;clear your calendar&amp;rdquo;-type event as it will ever be. On the morning of C-day, we got up early, loaded up with a hearty breakfast, filled the caffeine meter, and made sure we went to the bathroom before heading down to the T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We won the Cup!</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-15-we-won-the-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-15-we-won-the-cup/</guid>
      <description>Zdeno Chara grabbed hold of the Cup, reverently brought it to his lips, then raised it above his head, repeating a ritual performed by all previous Cup-winning captains. The only difference was that it had not been done by someone wearing the spoked-B since Nixon was President. The events of this night surely sent Bruins fans everywhere into a delirium. For the entire time that the Bruins celebrated on the ice, I had a stupidly wide grin on my face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We want the Cup!</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-14-we-want-the-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-14-we-want-the-cup/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the eve before the biggest game in my history as a Bruins fan. I&amp;rsquo;m so nervous I&amp;rsquo;m going to have problem going to sleep. I had known about hockey quite early on since Las Vegas had a minor-league team, the now-defunct Las Vegas Thunder, and a friend was a big fan. Despite knowing so little about the game, I was hooked immediately when I came to Boston in the mid-90s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The man they call Bobby</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-09-the-man-they-call-bobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-09-the-man-they-call-bobby/</guid>
      <description>TD Bank Garden, Boston on June 8, around 19:00. It was moments before Game 4 of the Stanley Cup finals between the Boston Bruins and the Vancouver Canucks. In the darkened arena, packed to the rafters with almost 18000 screaming fans, the lone spotlight descended on an area in the stands. Momentarily, a middle-aged man clad in a vintage Bruins jersey stepped into the light. The crowd erupted. It was none other than the legendary Bobby Orr, the man universally regarded as the finest defenseman in the history of hockey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
