<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>photography on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://yentran.org/categories/photography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in photography on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yentran.org/categories/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paris 1999</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-08-09-paris-flashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-08-09-paris-flashback/</guid>
      <description>I took a trip outside of the US for the first time in 1999. My sister and I got to spend a week in Paris, then took a train to the Netherlands where we toured the country for another week with a friend. Traveling so far from home by ourselves was exciting enough, and being in the most beautiful and metropolitan city in the world turned it into an unforgettable experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ollantaytambo, Peru (Day 6)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-08-07-ollantaytambo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-08-07-ollantaytambo/</guid>
      <description>On our last day in Peru, our flight from Cusco wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be until 15h30. Until then we could either wander around Cusco or use our Boleto Turístico to explore the other ruins on the outskirts of Cusco (Puca Pucara, Q&amp;rsquo;enqo and Tambomachay). However, we had heard really good things about Ollantaytambo. As it turned out, when we returned from Machu Picchu the night before, Lima Tours sent a driver to pick us up at Ollantaytambo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu, Peru (Day 5, 6)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-31-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-31-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike to Intipunku, the Inca Bridge and down to Aguas Calientes (the GPS track recorded by the logger is a little out of sync with Google Map, but you get the idea).
Had Machu Picchu been built in Cusco, it would have been just as spectacular. But being perched on a remote mountaintop, invisible from below, covered by swirling mists, and (when &amp;ldquo;discovered&amp;rdquo; by Hiram Bingham) overrun by the jungle gives it an unmatched mystique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sacsayhuamán, Peru (Day 4)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-24-sacsayhuaman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-24-sacsayhuaman/</guid>
      <description>The largest Inca complex in Cusco is Sacsayhuamán, a walled fortress which stands on a hill overlooking the city. It&amp;rsquo;s believed that the Incas built the city of Cusco in the shape of a jaguar, with Sacsayhuamán representing the head (and the most formidable part) of the jaguar. It may be hard to see it now, as the city has undergone dramatic changes in the intervening centuries. But it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see how the jagged outline of the walls bears remarkable resemblance to rows of teeth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Písac, Peru (Day 4)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-19-pisac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-19-pisac/</guid>
      <description>Map of our walking route of Písac.
Most people know about Cusco and Machu Picchu, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much more. Stretched between the two is the valley formed by the Urubamba (or Vilcanota) river, the so-called Sacred Valley of the Incas. Inca settlements, temples and monuments are found through the valley and towns such as Písac and Ollantaytambo are home to spectacular ruins. Those who are up for an outdoor experience can even take the Inca trail, the ancient highway to Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cusco, Peru (Day 3, 4, 6)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-17-cusco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-17-cusco/</guid>
      <description>We arrived at airport with just 1 hour to spare. I am quite impressed with LAN Chile Airline. Plenty of professional bilingual staff are available to assist passengers at automated check-in kiosks. Oh and they&amp;rsquo;re all attractive young women. In other parts of the world some old traditions still persist. Our flight to Cusco was short, about 1h. Our Peruvian fellow passenger was nice enough to stick the my GPS receiver behind the window shade so that we get a GPS trace of the flight path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lima, Peru (Day 1 &amp; 2)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-16-lima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-16-lima/</guid>
      <description>Our Peru adventure didn&amp;rsquo;t start out well. Our flight from Boston was delayed for 90 min and managed to land in Newark 5 minutes after the connection had already left. We were rerouted to Miami and put on a flight to Lima that arrived at 4:30 in the morning. The streets were mostly devoid of traffic though surprisingly some street sweepers were out working. Leaving the airport we scurried through a warren of narrow streets not unlike San Jose, Costa Rica, but soon things opened up when we got on the highway that runs along the ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revere Beach sand sculptures</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-15-revere-beach-sand-sculptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-15-revere-beach-sand-sculptures/</guid>
      <description>The annual Revere Beach sculpting festival concluded over the weekend. But since it hadn&amp;rsquo;t rained, we figured there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance the sculptures were still around. We got there around twilight, which was even better because the absence of mid-day shadows allowed the subtle details of the sculptures to come out.
Commemorating the 100th anniversary of Fenway Park.
Not sure what this represents, other than a study in perspectives.
The rather grotesque and provocatively Lovecraftian gorehound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Cadillac Mountain</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-08-acadia-national-park-cadillac-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-08-acadia-national-park-cadillac-mountain/</guid>
      <description>The tallest peak in Acadia and the first place in the continental US to see the morning light, Cadillac Mountain is also the most accessible &amp;ndash; you can just drive there. Nevertheless, its popularity doesn&amp;rsquo;t detract from its appeal. Unfortunately we couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it here early enough for sunrise, being worn out from hiking every day. So we had to settle for the &amp;ldquo;other golden hour&amp;rdquo;. Fortunately with a storm brewing in the distance all afternoon, we were treated to a beautiful sunset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berkshires 2010</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-04-04-berkshires-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-04-04-berkshires-2010/</guid>
      <description>Some highlights during my visit to the Berkshires in the autumn of 2010:
The Cascade (map): Trail head begins at the end of a very suburban road. Very limited street parking (think 2-3 spaces, depending on the skills of the driver). A short hike takes you over a nice wooden bridge as well as a fallen log-bridge. The waterfalls drops into a shallow pool at the trail.
Mount Greylock summit (map): The foliage on Mount Greylock was past-peak when we were there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn 2009</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-12-08-autumn-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-12-08-autumn-2009/</guid>
      <description>View location in Google Maps
Few places in Boston are as beautiful as Mount Auburn Cemetery. While it is famous as the final resting place of many luminaries with connection to New England, its more enduring legacy is as a green urban jewel. It would not be a stretch to invite comparison to Central Park. While not as popular, Mount Auburn is certainly more than an equal in aesthetic appeal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The doors of Boston</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-14-the-doors-of-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-14-the-doors-of-boston/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I saw a poster of doors. No, not these doors. I decided that I wanted one for myself. I picked Beacon Hill, a historic neighborhood known for its elegant houses and stately mansions. I biked around at dusk purposely so that the lights would be on, stopped frequently and snapped away. Some people, predictably, were wary of a stranger taking pictures of their homes. However, once I explained what I was doing, they were quite understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hub on Wheels 2010</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-10-hub-on-wheels-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-10-hub-on-wheels-2010/</guid>
      <description>Every September since 2005, the city of Boston has held a charity bike ride to benefit of one of its educational programs. The event is called Hub on Wheels, a clever pun based on Boston&amp;rsquo;s modest nickname for itself, the Hub of the Universe. For the majority of riders, it would be the only time of the year that they get an intimate view of some of Boston&amp;rsquo;s lesser-known neighborhoods. There are 3 available courses, 10-, 30- and 50-mile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Québec, 4-July</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-06-quebec-4-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-06-quebec-4-july/</guid>
      <description>Last morning in Québec. We took a 5-minute walk to check out the cool murals we saw earlier. These are quite amazing. A Gothic church exterior. An ornate stained-glass interior with a mysterious figure hooded in black. A ancient Aztec-meet-Egyptian structure surrounded by jungle. The best one yet was a castle with a red dragon, unfortunately obscured by the scaffolding for the Cirque de Soleil. I think you&amp;rsquo;d agree that these undoubtedly are the coolest highway underpasses anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Québec, 2-July</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-2-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-2-july/</guid>
      <description>At breakfast we ran into another Belgian couple, this time from Antwerp. They were on a tour of Ontario and Québec. They were quite excited about a free outdoor performance of the Cirque de Soleil. Sophie, who made us breakfast, also told us about the Moulin de l&amp;rsquo;Images, which was some sort of projection. We&amp;rsquo;d have to check both of them out.
We escaped from warm and muggy Boston to somewhat warm and muggy Québec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Québec, 3-July</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-3-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-3-july/</guid>
      <description>We had our fill of the city yesterday, so it seemed like time to head out to the country. We also learned that William and Kate would be in town as part of their Canada tour, an event undoubtedly to be attended by legions of their admirers and non-admirers alike. That cemented the decision for us. First stop is the Montmorency Falls. At 84 meters, it&amp;rsquo;s higher than Niagara Falls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn foliage 2010</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-23-foliage-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-23-foliage-2010/</guid>
      <description>In the autumn of 2010, a few friends and I spent a weekend in the White Mountains, New Hampshire and another in the Berkshires, Western Massachusetts. The former was a bit more adventurous. We went on a hike on North Moat Mountain and underestimated the terrain (or overestimated our ability). Even though we&amp;rsquo;re decent hikers and were appropriately equipped, 8-9 miles of strenuous hike coupled with a late start were our undoing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head of the Charles 2010</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-22-head-of-the-charles-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-22-head-of-the-charles-2010/</guid>
      <description>Every season in Boston has its own riveting appeal. The fall is not only the most beautiful of seasons, but it also marks the start of the hockey season and, for non-hockey fans, the annual Head of the Charles Regatta. In 2010, the Regatta took place on a chilly weekend in late October (this was Boston, after all). For me, there was nothing better than to put on a warm jacket, hop on the bike for the half-hour ride to Harvard University, then snap away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t trip and fall: The Chihuly exhibit</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-21-dont-trip-and-fall-the-chihuly-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-21-dont-trip-and-fall-the-chihuly-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday, we visited the Chihuly exhibit at the MFA. Like most people, I strained to find familiar words to describe something unfamiliar (during those moments when my mind wasn&amp;rsquo;t occupied with playing over and over the disastrous scenario of inadvertently knocking something down). Here are some of the ones I came up with. But sometimes, you just have to admit that there isn&amp;rsquo;t a word.
wavy pearlescent translucent veiny swirling fantastic alien bulbous metallic coppery rainbow writhing ghostly shimmering glowing sheet-like variegated striped spotted medusa crystalline fortress-of-solitude brilliant kaleidoscopic vivid silkworms frog-toes tentacled calamari tubular spiky light-saber agave</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring forward</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-29-spring-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-29-spring-forward/</guid>
      <description>Winter dragged its feel longer than usual this year. The first day of spring came and went, yet the dreariness continued well into April. There was even a minor snow storm on April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day, bringing to mind the epic blizzard of 1997. I remember that one well, having worked through the night to finish a problem set, only to find that class had been canceled and normally busy Memorial Drive had turned into a white graveyard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
