<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>art on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://yentran.org/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in art on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yentran.org/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Revere Beach sand sculptures</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-15-revere-beach-sand-sculptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-15-revere-beach-sand-sculptures/</guid>
      <description>The annual Revere Beach sculpting festival concluded over the weekend. But since it hadn&amp;rsquo;t rained, we figured there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance the sculptures were still around. We got there around twilight, which was even better because the absence of mid-day shadows allowed the subtle details of the sculptures to come out.
Commemorating the 100th anniversary of Fenway Park.
Not sure what this represents, other than a study in perspectives.
The rather grotesque and provocatively Lovecraftian gorehound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of The Fellowship of the Ring (The Lord of the Rings) by Gary Russell</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-09-07-the-art-of-the-fellowship-of-the-ring-the-lord-of-the-rings-by-gary-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-09-07-the-art-of-the-fellowship-of-the-ring-the-lord-of-the-rings-by-gary-russell/</guid>
      <description>Bringing Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s Middle Earth to life is a monumental task. The locations, creatures and monsters have to be conceptualized, designed and created from the ground up. Capturing the spirit of Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s work is an even more daunting challenge because of its tremendous scope, complexity and beauty. Furthermore, its legions of fans are staunch in their visions of Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s universe, and satisfying all of them is impossible.
That the movie has been a phenomenal success and, more importantly, an incredible realization of Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s visions is a testament to the skills and dedication of Peter Jackson and his team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
