<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>city on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://yentran.org/tags/city/</link>
    <description>Recent content in city on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yentran.org/tags/city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paris 1999</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-08-09-paris-flashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-08-09-paris-flashback/</guid>
      <description>I took a trip outside of the US for the first time in 1999. My sister and I got to spend a week in Paris, then took a train to the Netherlands where we toured the country for another week with a friend. Traveling so far from home by ourselves was exciting enough, and being in the most beautiful and metropolitan city in the world turned it into an unforgettable experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cusco, Peru (Day 3, 4, 6)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-17-cusco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-17-cusco/</guid>
      <description>We arrived at airport with just 1 hour to spare. I am quite impressed with LAN Chile Airline. Plenty of professional bilingual staff are available to assist passengers at automated check-in kiosks. Oh and they&amp;rsquo;re all attractive young women. In other parts of the world some old traditions still persist. Our flight to Cusco was short, about 1h. Our Peruvian fellow passenger was nice enough to stick the my GPS receiver behind the window shade so that we get a GPS trace of the flight path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lima, Peru (Day 1 &amp; 2)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-16-lima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-16-lima/</guid>
      <description>Our Peru adventure didn&amp;rsquo;t start out well. Our flight from Boston was delayed for 90 min and managed to land in Newark 5 minutes after the connection had already left. We were rerouted to Miami and put on a flight to Lima that arrived at 4:30 in the morning. The streets were mostly devoid of traffic though surprisingly some street sweepers were out working. Leaving the airport we scurried through a warren of narrow streets not unlike San Jose, Costa Rica, but soon things opened up when we got on the highway that runs along the ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The doors of Boston</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-14-the-doors-of-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-14-the-doors-of-boston/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I saw a poster of doors. No, not these doors. I decided that I wanted one for myself. I picked Beacon Hill, a historic neighborhood known for its elegant houses and stately mansions. I biked around at dusk purposely so that the lights would be on, stopped frequently and snapped away. Some people, predictably, were wary of a stranger taking pictures of their homes. However, once I explained what I was doing, they were quite understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hub on Wheels 2010</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-10-hub-on-wheels-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-10-hub-on-wheels-2010/</guid>
      <description>Every September since 2005, the city of Boston has held a charity bike ride to benefit of one of its educational programs. The event is called Hub on Wheels, a clever pun based on Boston&amp;rsquo;s modest nickname for itself, the Hub of the Universe. For the majority of riders, it would be the only time of the year that they get an intimate view of some of Boston&amp;rsquo;s lesser-known neighborhoods. There are 3 available courses, 10-, 30- and 50-mile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Québec, 4-July</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-06-quebec-4-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-06-quebec-4-july/</guid>
      <description>Last morning in Québec. We took a 5-minute walk to check out the cool murals we saw earlier. These are quite amazing. A Gothic church exterior. An ornate stained-glass interior with a mysterious figure hooded in black. A ancient Aztec-meet-Egyptian structure surrounded by jungle. The best one yet was a castle with a red dragon, unfortunately obscured by the scaffolding for the Cirque de Soleil. I think you&amp;rsquo;d agree that these undoubtedly are the coolest highway underpasses anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Québec, 1-July</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-1-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-1-july/</guid>
      <description>We decided to take off around 16:00 on Friday. In addition to the rush hour, we anticipated no fewer than 100000 Bostonians to be on the move for the long weekend. So we avoided the main highways altogether. Our plans worked, and when we re-connected with Interstate-93 North it was in Manchester, NH, some 60 miles away. The drive through the magnificent White Mountains was quite pleasant, as usual. Nevertheless, it was to be a very long drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Québec, 2-July</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-2-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-2-july/</guid>
      <description>At breakfast we ran into another Belgian couple, this time from Antwerp. They were on a tour of Ontario and Québec. They were quite excited about a free outdoor performance of the Cirque de Soleil. Sophie, who made us breakfast, also told us about the Moulin de l&amp;rsquo;Images, which was some sort of projection. We&amp;rsquo;d have to check both of them out.
We escaped from warm and muggy Boston to somewhat warm and muggy Québec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Québec, 3-July</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-3-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-07-05-quebec-3-july/</guid>
      <description>We had our fill of the city yesterday, so it seemed like time to head out to the country. We also learned that William and Kate would be in town as part of their Canada tour, an event undoubtedly to be attended by legions of their admirers and non-admirers alike. That cemented the decision for us. First stop is the Montmorency Falls. At 84 meters, it&amp;rsquo;s higher than Niagara Falls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head of the Charles 2010</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-22-head-of-the-charles-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-22-head-of-the-charles-2010/</guid>
      <description>Every season in Boston has its own riveting appeal. The fall is not only the most beautiful of seasons, but it also marks the start of the hockey season and, for non-hockey fans, the annual Head of the Charles Regatta. In 2010, the Regatta took place on a chilly weekend in late October (this was Boston, after all). For me, there was nothing better than to put on a warm jacket, hop on the bike for the half-hour ride to Harvard University, then snap away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t trip and fall: The Chihuly exhibit</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-21-dont-trip-and-fall-the-chihuly-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-21-dont-trip-and-fall-the-chihuly-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday, we visited the Chihuly exhibit at the MFA. Like most people, I strained to find familiar words to describe something unfamiliar (during those moments when my mind wasn&amp;rsquo;t occupied with playing over and over the disastrous scenario of inadvertently knocking something down). Here are some of the ones I came up with. But sometimes, you just have to admit that there isn&amp;rsquo;t a word.
wavy pearlescent translucent veiny swirling fantastic alien bulbous metallic coppery rainbow writhing ghostly shimmering glowing sheet-like variegated striped spotted medusa crystalline fortress-of-solitude brilliant kaleidoscopic vivid silkworms frog-toes tentacled calamari tubular spiky light-saber agave</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Bruins Stanley Cup Parade</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</guid>
      <description>Boston&amp;rsquo;s first Stanley Cup parade in 39 years was going to take place on Saturday, June 18, three days after the team celebrated on the ice in Vancouver. It was as definitive a &amp;ldquo;clear your calendar&amp;rdquo;-type event as it will ever be. On the morning of C-day, we got up early, loaded up with a hearty breakfast, filled the caffeine meter, and made sure we went to the bathroom before heading down to the T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Costa Rica Day 7 (Monday) - San Jose</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-30-costa-rica-day-7-monday-san-jose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-30-costa-rica-day-7-monday-san-jose/</guid>
      <description>The flight was to be at 13:00 so we planned on departing no later than 10:30. That left us about 1h after breakfast to explore downtown San Jose. We were 4 blocks away from the Jade Museum, which owns the largest collection of Pre-Columbian jade artifacts anywhere. Unfortunately a museum was out of the question given the time constraint.
Parque Morazán There are quite a few pleasant green spaces which serve to provide respite in the brick and concrete jungle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marblehead meander</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-29-marblehead-meander/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-29-marblehead-meander/</guid>
      <description>We discovered Marblehead sort of by accident. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it from an obscure television series in the late-80s called Marblehead Manor, which happened to star the then-equally obscure Michael Richards. One weekend we decided that it was too early to call it a night, so we took off on a drive out of Boston in a general northeasterly direction. We found ourselves at Revere Beach, which was deserted, and continued on Route 1A north to Lynn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
