<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RA Salvatore on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://yentran.org/tags/ra-salvatore/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RA Salvatore on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yentran.org/tags/ra-salvatore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Streams of Silver (Forgotten Realms: The Icewind Dale Trilogy, Book 2) by R. A. Salvatore</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-streams-of-silver-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-2-by-r-a-salvatore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-streams-of-silver-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-2-by-r-a-salvatore/</guid>
      <description>Good things come in trilogies and, in most cases, the second of the series is the best&amp;hellip;Streams of Silver is perhaps the zenith of the Icewind Dale trilogy. There are plenty of exciting adventures, desperate battles, horrifying monsters, devious sorcerers, dark dungeons, but most importantly, there is an element of the unknown. In the first novel, we all know the identity of the villain and what his nefarious plans are. Here, the companions, and the readers, have no idea what to expect, what horrible discovery they will make once they reach their destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Crystal Shard (Forgotten Realms: The Icewind Dale Trilogy, Book 1) by R. A. Salvatore</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-the-crystal-shard-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-1-by-r-a-salvatore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-the-crystal-shard-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-1-by-r-a-salvatore/</guid>
      <description>The main problem with works that are inspired by or that borrow from RPG is predictability. After all, what adventure would be complete without a warrior, a rogue, and a sorcerer. Not to mention the party must include a gruff dwarf and a light-hearted, pleasure-loving halfling. The Crystal Shard has got all that and more, but it also brings to life an original in the form of Drizzt Do&amp;rsquo;Urden, who&amp;rsquo;s undoubtedly one of the most well-known and beloved characters in fantasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Halfling&#39;s Gem (Forgotten Realms: The Icewind Dale Trilogy, Book 3) by R. A. Salvatore</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-the-halflings-gem-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-3-by-r-a-salvatore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-the-halflings-gem-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-3-by-r-a-salvatore/</guid>
      <description>The end of the second volume leads right into the third. As the companions escaped from Mithral Hall, Regis fell into the clutches of Artemis Entreri, the deadly assassin hired by the leader of the thieves&#39; guild in Calimport of whom Regis had run afoul. Furthermore, Entreri gained possession of the statuette that conjures the black panther Guenhwyvar, Drizzt&amp;rsquo;s faithful extra-planar companion. Saddened by the loss of Bruenor and now Regis, Drizzt and Wulfgar resolve to track down the assassin to his lair and rescue their friend, while Catti-Brie is grimly determined to finish Bruenor&amp;rsquo;s quest and retake Mithral Hall from the duergars.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
