<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hockey | Yen's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/categories/hockey/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-07T16:13:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Yen Tran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sports I would watch]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2014/02/07/sports-i-would-watch/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-07T10:07:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2014/02/07/sports-i-would-watch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&hellip;if I had an unlimited amount of free time, bathroom breaks and no desire to have a life.</p>

<ol>
<li>Olympic men&rsquo;s hockey</li>
<li>Bruins hockey</li>
<li>NHL hockey</li>
<li>IIHF tournament hockey such as the World Juniors</li>
<li>Top-flight European professional hockey (KHL, Swedish Elite League, Finnish Elite League)</li>
<li>Olympic women&rsquo;s hockey. It&rsquo;s enjoyable but less exciting than the men&rsquo;s game due to the lack of strong competition; basically it&rsquo;s a 2-horse race between Canada and USA. Also there&rsquo;s no checking and it&rsquo;s slower.</li>
<li>College hockey</li>
<li>AHL hockey</li>
<li>High school hockey</li>
<li>Tour de France</li>
<li>Other Summer and Winter Olympic sports</li>
<li>Bandy. I&rsquo;ve never seen this Swedish specialty, but this hockey-soccer hybrid is tantalizing. Putting the players on skates is one way to make soccer more exciting.</li>
<li>Pick-up hockey in a rink or on a pond</li>
<li>Roller hockey</li>
<li>Canadian shinny</li>
<li>European indoor roller hockey.  They play on rollerskates.  Seriously.  I&rsquo;ve only seen it a few times.  It&rsquo;s exciting and weird.</li>
<li>Figure skating</li>
<li>Midget/Bantam/Squirt/Mite hockey.  Midget is an official youth hockey designation, it doesn&rsquo;t mean the game is played by midgets, Borderlands-style.</li>
<li>Midget hockey, Borderlands-style</li>
<li>Street hockey</li>
<li>A couple of guys practicing with sticks and puck</li>
<li>Soccer</li>
<li>Volleyball (not beach)</li>
<li>Tennis</li>
</ol>


<p>&hellip; and many sports later</p>

<p>Football<br/>
Basketball<br/>
Baseball</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bruins took down Sabres in costly victory]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2013/10/23/bruins-took-down-sabres-in-costly-victory/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2013/10/23/bruins-took-down-sabres-in-costly-victory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was game 1 of the World Series.  Yawn. Since our pickup game was canceled in part due to the aforementioned sport&mdash;eh recreational&mdash;event, it was going to be either a work night or an early night.  Fortunately, the Bruins came to the rescue by taking on the Sabres.  It&rsquo;s a good thing it was on NBCSports/Versus instead of NESN, where viewers would have been bombarded with a constant barrage of WS updates, even though the network TV announcers are downright annoying. The Bruins welcome the undefeated Sharks tomorrow at home, but tonight would be a Bear-Buffalo grudge match.</p>

<p>The game was billed as a Wednesday Rivalry Game.  The Bruins' record was 5-2 and the Sabres 1-8-1, so these were clearly two teams headed in different directions. In fact, it hasn&rsquo;t been much of a rivalry since they last faced each other in the 2nd round of the 2009-10 playoffs.  The Sabres have not made the playoffs in the last two years.  They have the second worst record in the league.  The only other team with a similarly dismal record, the Broadstreet Bumblers, got their coach fired just 3 games into the season.  Nevertheless, the Sabres were one of the few teams with a winning record against the Bruins last season and, like the Canadiens, always seem to find ways to beat the Bruins.</p>

<p>But it wouldn&rsquo;t happen tonight. Just from this game, it was clear why they&rsquo;ve been struggling.  They were terrible in their zone. They got beat to the puck.  They got beat in one-on-one battles. They weren&rsquo;t strong enough on the puck carrier to get it back. On offense, they weren&rsquo;t playing as a team.  Skilled guys tried to make plays by themselves.  Cody Hodgson tried to  take on 4 Bruins defenders on the power play&mdash;that doesn&rsquo;t work even in peewee hockey. Guys were taking themselves off-sides. They were a terribly disorganized team who seemed unfocused and unconfident. And then there was John Scott, a 6'8, 260-lb monster who looks vaguely like Liev Schreiber.  By NHL standards, he can barely skate (even though he&rsquo;s better than every normal person and probably most minor leaguers).  He&rsquo;s there to intimidate and even terrorize.  Just <a href="http://sports.yahoo.com/blogs/nhl-puck-daddy/john-scott-explains-why-attacked-poor-nearly-defenseless-202830725--nhl.html">ask Phil Kessel</a>.  Admittedly, in hockey, particularly &ldquo;old-time hockey&rdquo;, being intimidating can sometimes have as much of an impact as being skillful.</p>

<p>The lone bright spot for the Sabres had to be Ryan Miller.  The Bruins had odd-man rushes all night.  Despite the lopsided score, it would have been much worse if it weren&rsquo;t for him. He made several outstanding saves that would have gotten by lesser goalies. The most sparkling save was on a tic-tac-toe play that started on one side of the net and ended on the other with with David Krejci catching the puck on his backhand and quickly flipping it with his forehand, only to be robbed by Miller&rsquo;s glove. Of the goals he gave up, three were perfect backdoor plays that he had no chance on. One he would have stopped if his stick hadn&rsquo;t been pushed out of position by a falling teammate.  Only the last one was somewhat saveable, but by then the game was out of reach.</p>

<p>The Bruins' 5-2 victory was marred by an ugly incident. Long after he had released the puck, Loui Eriksson was blindsided by Scott with a hit to the head that spun him around and knocked him to the ground.  He struggled to get up but stumbled, clearly disoriented. This is a scary hit that was eerily reminiscent of the Matt Cooke hit on Marc Savard that ended Savard&rsquo;s promising career.  Eriksson was woozy and had to be helped off the ice. One can only hope that his long-term health isn&rsquo;t compromised.  He&rsquo;s undoubtedly lost for tomorrow night&rsquo;s game, if not longer.  This type of hits, where the &ldquo;head is the principal area of contact&rdquo;, is something the league has been trying to stamp out.  Already several multi-game suspensions have been handed out this season for similar plays.  It&rsquo;s quite expected that the league will come down hard on Scott.</p>

<p>The Bruins responded with Adam McQuaid tackling Scott and wrestling him down.  Perhaps that was enough.  I&rsquo;m not one to demand that the Bruins respond to a dirty play with dirty plays of their own.  It&rsquo;s important to many hockey fans that the team stand up for their teammates.  After the Savard incident, the Bruins were criticized by some for their lack of response. Maybe Shawn Thornton will take on Scott the next time they meet (provided Scott is playing), but it wouldn&rsquo;t be good for Thornton given that Scott is in a totally different weight class.  Maybe someone will engage Steve Ott, another dirty Sabre (his sucker punch on Krejci went unnoticed by the refs).  I really think a more measured response is to make them pay on the scoreboard.  The Bruins did just that, by scoring a goal on the PP resulting from Scott&rsquo;s major penalty.  If Scott&rsquo;s action was a intended as &ldquo;message-sending&rdquo;, it already failed, because experience has shown that when faced with adversity, this team becomes stronger.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bruins Training Camp 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/bruins-training-camp-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/bruins-training-camp-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having moved to the &lsquo;burbs recently, I look forward to attending the Bruins&rsquo; regular-season practice sessions at Ristuccia Arena in Wilmington, now that it&rsquo;s only a few miles away.  The 2013 Training Camp, though, was held at TD Garden the weekend of September 14-15. Of course I was going to be there.</p>

<p>The 2013 season was a bit of a roller coaster ride.  It was thrilling at times, but ultimately disappointing. It was a hard pill to swallow watching the Blackhawks celebrate with the Cup on our ice. Then came the off-season changes.  The departures of Tyler Seguin and Rich Perveley were certainly shocking, particularly Seguin who were expected to be the next Bruins superstar. Then came the arrival of Jarome Iginla, whom most Bruins fans including myself were gleefully cheering against especially during the Penguins series.  Seeing Iginla wearing the spoked B would be a little weird, to say the least.  Even the anticipated free-agency departures of popular Bruins Nathan Horton (to Columbus) and Andrew Ference (to Edmonton) were hard to take. I like Ference in particular, for his leadership qualities and environmental activism.  It didn&rsquo;t help matter that a very solid goalie and likeable player in Anton Khudobin also left, which was a surprise.</p>

<p>Having endured the summer of baseball and the start of football season, I am beyond thrill at the return of hockey.  Judging from the turnout for the training camp, despite the early weekend hours, many Bruins fans were feeling the same way.  Part of the eagerness must come from anticipating the new faces on the roster.  But for the most part, I just wanted to spectate the most exciting team sports invented by man.</p>

<p>The Training Camp consisted of 2 groups.  With 50-odd participants and only a few open roster spots, it was clear that most of the new guys were going to end up elsewhere, whether with the baby Bruins in Providence, their junior/college team or some place like Saskatoon.  Nevertheless, it was a chance for the coaches to evaluate players or for fans like me to familiarize ourselves with our prospects.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m guessing the opening-day roster will look something like this:</p>

<p>Milan Lucic (17) &ndash; David Krejci (46) &ndash; Jarome Iginla (12)<br/>
Brad Marchand (63) &ndash; Patrice Bergeron (37) &ndash; Loui Eriksson (21)<br/>
Carl Soderberg (34) &ndash; Chris Kelly (23) &ndash; ???<br/>
Daniel Paille (20) &ndash; Gregory Campbell (11) &ndash; Shawn Thornton (22)</p>

<p>Zdeno Chara (33) &ndash; Johnny Boychuk (55)<br/>
Dennis Seidenberg (44) &ndash; Dougie Hamilton (27)<br/>
??? &ndash; Adam McQuaid (54)</p>

<p>Tuukka Rask (40)<br/>
???</p>

<p>On defense, Matt Bartkowski (43) and Torey Krug (47), both left-shots, are likely candidates.  Both played last season, Krug having stood out in the Rangers series.  Local guy David Warsofsky is probably also in consideration.  The empty forward and goalie spots are wide-open. That&rsquo;s why we&rsquo;re here.</p>

<p>Seth Griffith misses an open-net chance on Niklas Svedberg.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1460.jpg' /></p>

<p>Dennis Seidenberg patrols the blue line on his unusual t-blade.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1479.jpg' /></p>

<p>Crowd around Svedberg.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1533.jpg' /></p>

<p>Chris Kelly cirling the net.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1535.jpg' /></p>

<p>New signee Matthew Lindblad trying to get a bead on Tuukka Rask.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1564.jpg' /></p>

<p>Brad Marchand buzzes the net as usual.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1740.jpg' /></p>

<p>Patrice Bergeron looks to be in full form after the serious injuries sustained in the Blackhawks series.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1644.jpg' /></p>

<p>Newcomer Loui Eriksson (21) drives to the net, guarded by Dougie Hamilton (27).</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1614.jpg' /></p>

<p>Another look at Eriksson.  He seemed to be an open-ice player who isn&rsquo;t afraid of going to the crease. He&rsquo;s bigger than Seguin and has good speed. The demise of our team speed with the departures of Seguin and Peverley is greatly exaggerated.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1712.jpg' /></p>

<p>Jordan Caron (38) and Reilly Smith. Caron has been up and down with the big club. Of all the young guys he probably has the most NHL experience. Maybe he can stick around this time.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1680.jpg' /></p>

<p>Chris Casto in full flight.  Hockey players can look like they&rsquo;re sprinting.  Actually, it&rsquo;s not quite true. They&rsquo;re much faster than a sprinter.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1716.jpg' /></p>

<p>Marchand trying to shake off Hamilton.  That&rsquo;s probably not a great gap for Hamilton, but you can&rsquo;t stay too close to Marchand or he&rsquo;ll make you look bad.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1755.jpg' /></p>

<p>Mike Moore finds out the hard way where the goal post is.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1634.jpg' /></p>

<p>Hamilton should probably be between his check and the net instead of chasing him but, meh, it&rsquo;s practice. He&rsquo;s huge, at 6'5 he&rsquo;s second only to Chara.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1747.jpg' /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h15m87WsCHQ">This gutsy display of sportsmanship and determination</a> after his leg was broken by an Evgeni Malkin slapshot made Gregory Campbell a Bruin forever. This isn&rsquo;t Lionel Messi crying after he got tripped.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2170.jpg' /></p>

<p>Matt Bartkowski sees something wince-worthy. On the right is Carl Soderberg.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1845.jpg' /></p>

<p>Adam McQuaid with a rare smile.  In the background Shawn Thornton juggles the puck on the blade of his stick. The tough guy has mad skillz.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1911.jpg' /></p>

<p>Milan Lucic having a laugh with (or at?) Bartkowski.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1920.jpg' /></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going with &ldquo;laugh with&rdquo;. Bart is such a jokester.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_1931.jpg' /></p>

<p>Chara having a chat with Nick Johnson (32) and Alexander Fallstrom (59).  Those are not midgets&mdash;both are listed at 6'2. Chara is just a monster, and I mean that in an admiring way.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2023.jpg' /></p>

<p>He can move too.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2111.jpg' /></p>

<p>New &ldquo;old&rdquo; face Jarome Iginla.  He potted 2 against the Habs two nights after this in a pre-season game in Montreal. Welcome to Boston, Iggy.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2040.jpg' /></p>

<p>Lucic with a wicked snap shot.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2051.jpg' /></p>

<p>The 3rd member of the projected top line and my favorite player.  The bruising line of Lucic-Iginla-Krejci is going to give defensemen nightmares. They have great hands, decent speed, hit like a train and are impossible to contain.  They bring back fond memories of the so-called 700 Pound Line of Joe Thornton, Mike Knuble and Glen Murray.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2123.jpg' /></p>

<p>Torey Krug with Mark Messier&rsquo;s patented snap shot off the wrong leg. Which, by the way, everyone is using these days.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2062.jpg' /></p>

<p>Fallstrom with a good flex of the stick.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2073.jpg' /></p>

<p>A first look at Malcolm Subban.  You know, the brother of Boston&rsquo;s public enemy #1 PK Subban. He did say he never liked his brother anyways. The kid is all right.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2100.jpg' /></p>

<p>Kevan Miller who hails from, get this, Los Angeles.  That&rsquo;s right, a California kid playing pro hockey.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2108.jpg' /></p>

<p>Close-up of Daniel Paille.</p>

<p><img src='https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/bruins-2013/dsc_2150.jpg' /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You played with who?]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2013/03/08/you-played-with-who/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2013/03/08/you-played-with-who</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since 1999 I&rsquo;ve helped run a pickup hockey group at the Skating Club of Boston.  We&rsquo;re really not crazy about the rink there.  The ice is intended for figure skaters so it&rsquo;s soft and thus slow and quick to become choppy.  There is no glass above the boards so if you shoot high enough you&rsquo;d have to go fish for the puck under the stands. And since figure skaters generally stay in the middle of the ice, the edges are neglected and not well maintained; this is a problem if you try to &ldquo;wrap the puck around the board&rdquo;. Nevertheless, the location is great and we got to know the rink manager there quite well.  He gives us extra ice time and at the end of the year we try to return the favor by collecting to give him a nice X-mas check.</p>

<p>Our group started off as a bunch of friends who played intramural hockey at MIT together.  Over the years, people have come and gone, but I&rsquo;m the only constant. Since I still put the roster together every week, year round, I&rsquo;ve gotten to know a bit about the people who have played with us. I guess I could say I&rsquo;m a sort of unofficial historian.  Because of our academic origin, we&rsquo;ve always had a strong contingent of people with advanced degrees.  We&rsquo;ve had several PhDs, MDs and lawyers.  A few are current professors at local universities.  But probably thanks to hockey&rsquo;s grassroots appeal, I&rsquo;m amazed at the diversity we&rsquo;ve had.  We&rsquo;ve had cops, EMTs, firefighters,  architects, engineers, scientists, pilots, artists, designers, writers, tech entrepreneurs, a maître d’hôtel, a restauranteur, a couple of finance guys, a bunch of software guys.  Indie singers and DJs have leaped over the boards.  Which is somewhat surprising because we obviously have no marketing department.  It&rsquo;s probably just word of mouth or pure serendipity that some of these guys end up playing with us.  Over the years, there are some note-worthy names who have laced up the skates with us. So far as I remember here are some.</p>

<ul>
<li>The 1999 World Junior Ice Dancing champion</li>
<li>A Boston Police superintendent and head of the Bureau of Investigative Services</li>
<li>The platform director at Twitter</li>
<li>The founder of Colorkinetics (now Philips)</li>
<li>The former CEO of Akamai</li>
<li>The current general manager of the Red Sox. He&rsquo;s a quiet, good player who liked to be on defense. One of the complaints I remembered was that he didn&rsquo;t get off the ice very much.</li>
<li>The bassist for the punk band NOFX.  He just showed up at the rink with a hockey bag. The other guys told him to wait to check with me whether he could play (we don&rsquo;t want too many skaters).  We had room so he stayed.  Turned out he was in town for a concert and, being a hockey enthusiast and player, he brought his gears along. Apparently he does this on road trips.  Not all of us have heard of NOFX, but those who did were quite excited when they found out.  He was only an average player, but does possess first-class enthusiasm.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Bruins' 2011 White House appearance]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2012/01/23/on-the-bruins-2011-white-house-appearance/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2012/01/23/on-the-bruins-2011-white-house-appearance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/23/president-obama-welcomes-boston-bruins"><img title="Bruins 2011 White House photo" src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/images/20120123-potus-boston-bruins.jpg" width="560" height="373" /></a></p>

<p>Today the Bruins appeared at the White House where President Obama greeted them and honored their accomplishments as 2011 Stanley Cup champions. Included in the group photo were Americans, Canadians, Czechs, a Slovak, a Finn, and a German. Notable in his absence was Bruins goalie Tim Thomas, Stanley Cup playoffs MVP, winner of multiple awards and the only American player who made significant contribution to the team&rsquo;s Cup run. The details of Thomas' absence are covered elsewhere, but it has become clear that it is politically motivated.</p>

<p>Thomas is known for many things&mdash;his unorthodox style, his underdog status, his fierce competitiveness, his infectious grin, his modesty, his loyalty to teammates, and his classy behavior. In the Stanley Cup Finals series, after beating the Bruins in game 5, Vancouver goalie Roberto Luongo publicly made disparaging remarks about Thomas' playing style. Thomas kept quiet and focused on his own play. The Bruins proceeded to embarrass Luongo in game 6 and Thomas shut out the Canucks in the final and deciding game. Even though he was vindicated, Thomas refrained from responding in kind to Luongo, even when he was presented with many opportunities to do so by the media.</p>

<p>What does being classy mean? Despite being overused, it is still a neat little word which does its job so well so succinctly. To me it means the willingness to do the right thing even if one is averse or opposed to it. The &ldquo;right&rdquo; thing depends a great deal on one&rsquo;s perspective. Yet there are many qualities such as honor, loyalty and respect that can be considered to be universally admired.  Having known little about Thomas' personal life, today&rsquo;s events came as a surprise and ultimately a disappointment for me.</p>

<p>The White House appearance is a long-standing tradition in which the President fetes (an American) professional sports champion. It is a ceremonial event with little, if any, political benefit for the President. It is an event in which the team&rsquo;s achievements are recognized by the highest office in the land. It is an occasion for the players to congratulate and honor each other. But it is not only for the athletes. It is also an honor for the club, the coaches, the general manager, the staff, the front office and the owners. Just as importantly, it is a significant honor for a large number of Bruins fans, who have not celebrated a championship in 39 years&mdash;or, for many, ever.</p>

<p>In consideration of his teammates, his employers and his fans, the right thing for Thomas to do would be to appear with the team, regardless of his political leaning. The most cherished of hockey traditions is the handshake at center ice following the conclusion of a playoffs series. This tradition exudes sportsmanship and embodies the widely admired qualities of respecting one&rsquo;s opponent and being gracious in victory and defeat. Thomas shook hands with Vancouver players who fought, hacked, slashed, bit, taunted his teammates and friends, even viciously knocking out one of them. If it was okay to shake hands with bitter opponents, would it not be okay to shake hands with someone who doesn&rsquo;t share his political convictions? With his absence, Thomas refused to show respect to the President. More seriously, by standing apart from his teammates, he undermines the very foundation of a Bruins team that prides itself on unity and allegiance to one another. Thomas, it pains me to say that this is not a classy move on your part.</p>

<p>Overshadowed in the reactions to Thomas' decision is how Bruins general manager Peter Chiarelli handled the situation. Chiarelli could have made the visit mandatory and suspended Thomas if he was a no-show. He did neither. He chose the least disruptive course of actions. While he tried for some time to convince Thomas, in the end he left it up to him. In Chiarelli&rsquo;s words, &ldquo;We&rsquo;re like a family. We have our issues. You deal with them, move on, and try and support everyone.&rdquo; Chiarelli did the right thing and took utmost care to balance the interest of the team and of the individual. As Chiarelli said, Thomas is a part of the Bruins family&mdash;a very important part. Even if a family member does something you don&rsquo;t agree with, you still support him.  I will cheer for and wish Thomas continued success on and off the ice. It&rsquo;s the only classy thing to do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
