<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: review | Yen's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/categories/review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-24T15:39:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Yen Tran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sigma 50mm f/1.4 lens for Nikon AF]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2013/11/13/sigma-50mm-lens/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2013/11/13/sigma-50mm-lens</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m fond of landscape photography.  However when there&rsquo;s a human subject, applying the same kind of composition can come out looking too formal or posed.  I&rsquo;d like to achieve more of the natural, spontaneous, spur-of-the-moment feel.  For that I want to have a lens that&rsquo;s fast, focuses quickly and has good bokeh.  A prime lens would have those qualities at a much lower price point than a telephoto lens.  With that settled, I had to decide between 35, 50 and 85mm.  From what I&rsquo;ve read, the general opinion is that the wide-angle 35mm prime lens is good for landscape or street scenes, while 85mm is good for an intimate, close-up portrait.  That leaves the 50mm, which can do either almost as well and happens to be the (only) lens on my first camera, a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canon_AT-1">Canon AT-1</a>.  That it&rsquo;s famously associated with Henri Cartier-Bresson can&rsquo;t be a bad thing either.</p>

<p>Nikon offers two 50mm lenses at f/1.4 and f/1.8.  I chose the Sigma 50mm f/1.4 over the Nikon counterparts. For one, the reviews for the Sigma are universally outstanding.  Even though bokeh quality is somewhat subjective, the general consensus is that the Sigma is better. For almost the same price as the Nikon 50mm f/1.4, it looks and feels much more solid than the plasticky-looking Nikon equivalent. Furthermore, it has the professional-standard 77mm filter size instead of the 58mm and 52mm filter sizes for the Nikon lenses.</p>

<p>The Sigma is very solid with a nice heft. It&rsquo;s plastic, but manages to feel upscale and not cheap.  It comes with a canvas pouch, a lens hood and a lens cover. It&rsquo;s made in Japan, which is nice for a lens at this price range.  Even my much more expensive Nikon 24-120mm f/4 zoom is made in Thailand.  Strangely, there&rsquo;s no marker on the lens to line up with the camera body, so I had to fiddle around a bit to get it to screw in.</p>

<p>Now onto the test images. All photos are taken with a Nikon D600 in either aperture priority or manual mode with auto ISO sensitivity. The first shoot is a walkaround our neighborhood.</p>

<p>This is a rather clich&eacute; shot.  The subject is flat so all of it can be in focus. I thought the sharpness is very good.
<figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_5105.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 1/1000 @ f/1.8, 100 ISO</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>Here Kate is inspecting our walkway. In daylight the lens focuses easily. I think focusing works best at this distance.  Depth of field is good with the lens wide open and so is bokeh. The 50mm focal length is perfect for portraits that include the upper body or shoulder.
<figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_5096.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 1/1250 @ f/1.8, 100 ISO</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>I love this shot, and not just because of the subject.  Because of the closeness, I had to stop down the aperture a bit while focusing on the eyes.  Otherwise the other parts of the face would be out of focus.
<figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_5059.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 1/50 @ f/5, 1800 ISO</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>The second shoot was at a ballroom competition at Tufts University where my friends were competing. Here I put the D600 in continuous servo AF mode with 9 focusing points.  I shot in manual mode with the shutter speed set at a sufficiently high value to prevent blurring. I also <a href="http://www.luminescentphoto.com/blog/2010/11/05/nikon-af-on-technique">set the AE/AL button to AF-on</a> so that shutter release button just, well, release.</p>

<p>This is a rather flashy couple that clearly dominated the rest of the field.  They were quite adept at showmanship.  Not surprisingly, they took first place.<br/>
<figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_5164.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 1/400 @ f/2.2, 720 ISO</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>Here they are practicing in the corridor above the main floor.  The setting is very nice, as is the photogenic couple. This has almost an Instagram feel to it.
<figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_5335.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 1/400 @ f/1.8, 3200 ISO</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>This is at the maximum aperture.  Again sharpness is excellent at a range of about 3m.  I had several long-distance shots from around 20-40m with continuous servo AF that didn&rsquo;t turn out very good.  The subject was blurry while the background was in sharper focus. Either the autofocus wasn&rsquo;t working well, or I just didn&rsquo;t have the right setting.  I switched from 9- to 21-point focusing mode and got somewhat better results.  In general I think this lens suits close-ups better.
<figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_5377.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 1/400 @ f/1.4, 2800 ISO</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_5312.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 400 @ f/2.2, 3200 ISO</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>The last shoot is at a friend&rsquo;s house. I had to use continuous focusing again because the subject was rather, ahem, mobile.  Some shots turned out quite blurry even with high shutter speed.  I&rsquo;ll have to look into this more.  This shows the nice subject isolation possible with the ridiculously large aperture.
<figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_5737.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 1/60 @ f/1.4, 450 ISO</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p><figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_5938.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 1/160 @ f/2.2, 3200 ISO</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p><figure>
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/sigma-50mm/dsc_6000.jpg" />
<figcaption>Exposure 1/160 @ f/2.2, 2800 ISO</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>In conclusion, I love this lens! I like the ability to just point and shoot without worrying too much about composition.  Being so used to carefully composing a shot, I&rsquo;ve had to resist that impulse a bit and just focus on capturing the moment as it happens.  The results look and feel natural and effortless.   Needless to say this lens will get a lot more work in the future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looper]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2012/11/04/looper/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2012/11/04/looper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looper, starring Bruce Willis and that awkward kid in Third Rock from the Sun, is a terrific movie with extraordinary storytelling, tightly woven narrative and great acting. I really enjoy it very much, despite some misgivings about its remorseless violence and relentlessly depressing depiction of the future. However, since I&rsquo;ve been asked if I can poke any hole in it, I&rsquo;ve taken it upon myself as a task to find a chink or two in the movie&rsquo;s formidable armor, much in the same spirit as <a href="http://www.juliansanchez.com/2012/06/11/whats-wrong-with-prometheus-a-partial-list">this critique</a>. There are probably a few holes in my own armor, as I&rsquo;ve only sat through the movie once and may miss details here and there. Needless to say, this is going to contain <strong>massive spoilers</strong>. I mean, it&rsquo;s pretty much going to give whole the movie away. So if you haven&rsquo;t seen the movie and would like to at some point, you will not want to read further. With that disclaimer out of the way, here goes.</p>

<ul>
<li>Joe (Joseph Gordon-Levitt) and others like him are Loopers, hired killers who execute prisoners sent from the future by an criminal syndicate via a time machine. The Looper waits at a certain location, typically in the middle of a field or in an abandoned courtyard. At the appointed time, the victim appears in front of them, tied and hooded. He pulls the trigger, removes the payment in the form of silver bars taped to the back of the victim, and disposes of the body in a furnace. Things are done this way, we&rsquo;re told, because in the future, it&rsquo;s very difficult to make people disappear without a trace. My question is, the criminals could operate a time machine but couldn&rsquo;t find a way to operate an incinerator?</li>
<li>The criminals go through the trouble of sending a man to the past to recruit and manage the Loopers and deal with things that could go wrong (which does). They risk polluting the time line if the victims end up escaping (they do). This seems like a needlessly complex scheme fraught with risk. Couldn&rsquo;t they just send the victim back 10,000 years or so where he would have perished without so much as a ding on the timeline. Okay, so maybe the time machine has a limited range and only works for the last 30 years or so. Couldn&rsquo;t they have set one up in the middle of a lake or just off shore? Make sure the victim is weighed down and he would just disappear beneath the waves.</li>
<li>The Looper is given the time on a piece of paper and the victim appears exactly at the appointed time. Nevermind the fact that they have to synchronize their watches over, oh, 30 years or so, how do they send a message from the future to set the time?</li>
<li>While future-Joe (Bruce Willis) followed present-Joe back to his apartment, he walked across an open garage and shot a thug sitting inside a car. Given that present-Joe is only armed with a blunderbuss&mdash;which he keeps on him&mdash;when future-Joe steals his truck, where does future-Joe get a gun?</li>
<li>For being professional killers, the thugs are horrendous shots. The one on top of the balcony at present-Joe&rsquo;s apartment keeps missing future-Joe who is only 30&mdash;40 feet away. Near the end, Kid Blue with his peashooter, again keeps missing present-Joe by a mile (though he was riding a hoverbike which makes aiming difficult).</li>
<li>Future-Seth ends up escaping. Under interrogation, present-Joe gives away present-Seth, who is captured. While future-Seth is running away, his fingers and leg begin to disappear and a tattoo appears on his forearm with an address. Mutilated, he barely makes it to the address, whereupon he is promptly shot. Apparently the bad guys mutilate present-Seth to directly affect future-Seth. This is a terrific setup for what would happen later in the movie. Nevertheless, since the goal is to get rid of the Seths, couldn&rsquo;t they just have killed present-Seth?</li>
<li>Loopers are dismissed with a final payment of gold bars. They know that in 30 years they would be captured and sent back to be executed, thus closing the loop. With the knowledge and the means, future-Joe does nothing to avoid this fate?</li>
<li>The in the &ldquo;flash forward&rdquo;, Joe goes to China. As the year goes by, he gets older. All of a sudden, he turns from Joseph Gordon-Levitt who has shoulder-length black hair into Bruce Willis who is 30 years older and almost completely bald.</li>
<li>The entire diner empties out without neither present- or future-Joe, who sit in the middle of it, noticing.</li>
<li>At the diner shootout, present-Joe joins the thugs in shooting at future-Joe. The thugs completely ignore present-Joe without realizing that with him they have immediate and lethal leverage over the other.</li>
<li>Kid Blue, on the tracks of future-Joe, goes to a guy who shows him a video feed of future-Joe approaching and peeking into the window of the prostitute&rsquo;s apartment. It seems like an extraordinary coincidence that he finds the right guy who has access to the right camera at the right location in a huge metropolis.</li>
<li>Most of the cars have tubes or pipes running around the rear, presumably into the fuel door. What is the purpose of the pipes? If they carry some sort of fuel, as is the most likely explanation, why leave them exposed in the back vulnerable to a rear-end collision or mischief.</li>
</ul>


<p>In all fairness, this is a very well-written and -executed movie. These are minor nitpicks and by no means should detract from your enjoyment of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Redemption of Althalus by David & Leigh Eddings]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2011/09/07/the-redemption-of-althalus-by-david-leigh-eddings/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2011/09/07/the-redemption-of-althalus-by-david-leigh-eddings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="pull-left" title="althalus" src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/images/althalus.jpg" width="186" height="272" />Having plowed through three multi-volume fantasy series in a row, I thought this single-volume tome, the first standalone fantasy adventure by the husband-and-wife team, might be a welcome respite. I haven&rsquo;t read any book by the Eddingses, but their reputation as prolific and popular authors is well-known. I was further intrigued by the &ldquo;#1 international bestseller&rdquo; plug emblazoned on the hardcover.</p>

<p>The title character is a thief and occasional highwayman and murderer whose skills are legendary. He&rsquo;s also a braggart and a liar of epic proportions. Plagued by a streak of uncharacteristic bad luck, he accepts a job from a shady character to steal a Book in the House at the End of the World. He finds the Book but is detained by a talking cat, who is in reality the goddess Dweia in disguise. Dweia persuades him to be her agent, and they recruit others to join their team, including a warrior, a priest, a queen, a mind-reader, and a young thief. Together they engage in epic struggles with agents of the Evil God, who seeks to undo all creation and return the universe to nothingness.</p>

<p>That the names of the authors are in larger fonts than the title of the book should have been a warning bell, I suppose. To be fair, the story is somewhat interesting. The concept of a House that compresses space and time, and that allows one to travel vast distances or time by simply going down the hallway, is a novel idea. Throw in a few modern concepts, such as the time-space duality and even the procedure for rudimentary brain surgery, and the story has a distinct sci-fi feel. Nevertheless, the plot is more or less predictable, straightforward action-adventure with a smattering of romance: Althalus and friends recruit an army, goes here, repel an invasion, fall in love, goes there, fight another war, go some place else, defeat the bad guys, etc. The pace is, for lack of a better word, unchanged. It&rsquo;s the same whether the characters are cuddling or fighting for their lives. The authors seem to be on cruise control throughout; they seem to be recounting a story fact by fact, instead of portraying it, making it come alive. The feeling is comparable to watching a documentary film versus an action movie or drama. The cookie-cutter characters are rather flat and two-dimensional. So they are all different in their attributes and abilities, but nothing else distinguishes one from the other. They all make the same cliche wisecracks, punts, or sarcastic remarks. Some merit a chuckle or two, but after a while one is left to wonder whether or not there is anything else to them. In fact, I can&rsquo;t even envision what each character looks like; I&rsquo;d like to see more than just tall/short, big/tiny, dark-haired/blond, beautiful/ugly, etc. Contrast this with the works of some other authors, such as George Martin, who lavishes attention on the description of the wardrobe alone. Of course, characterization goes beyond superficial appearance. There are other means, such as describing how events unfold from the character&rsquo;s point of view, that can bring the point across. Unfortunately such richness and attention to details are absent here. Similarly, the writing is competent, but lacks a certain sophistication and seriousness demonstrated by some other authors. The book is entertaining if you&rsquo;re in the mood for casual reading, and I feel that it would be most appropriate for a younger audience rather than a serious fantasy fan.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted January 5, 2003 on Amazon.com</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Halfling's Gem (Forgotten Realms: The Icewind Dale Trilogy, Book 3) by R. A. Salvatore]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2011/09/07/the-halflings-gem-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-3-by-r-a-salvatore/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2011/09/07/the-halflings-gem-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-3-by-r-a-salvatore</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="pull-left" title="the_halflings_gem" src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/images/the_halflings_gem-178x300.jpg" width="178" height="300" />The end of the second volume leads right into the third. As the companions escaped from Mithral Hall, Regis fell into the clutches of Artemis Entreri, the deadly assassin hired by the leader of the thieves' guild in Calimport of whom Regis had run afoul. Furthermore, Entreri gained possession of the statuette that conjures the black panther Guenhwyvar, Drizzt&rsquo;s faithful extra-planar companion. Saddened by the loss of Bruenor and now Regis, Drizzt and Wulfgar resolve to track down the assassin to his lair and rescue their friend, while Catti-Brie is grimly determined to finish Bruenor&rsquo;s quest and retake Mithral Hall from the duergars.</p>

<p>After the excitement of volume two, there is a bit of a let-down. After all, the action doesn&rsquo;t really pick up until Drizzt and Wulfgar near the end of their destination. After that, all hell breaks loose, literally. What follows is non-stop action. The party must survive an ambush in the city sewers, find an exit through the trap-filled thieves' guild, and escape from an an astral plane filled with bloodthirsty demons. All the while, Drizzt is drawn inexorably toward a confrontation with Entreri, who&rsquo;s his equal in every physical aspect and martial skill, yet is his polar opposite in spirit and morality. As expected, Drizzt&rsquo;s duel with Entreri is the highlight of the story, though unfortunately it ends without a resolution. Drizzt&rsquo;s emotional saga continues, as he struggles to be comfortable with his physical appearance, and succeeds in gaining a small measure of acceptance by the nobility of his actions. Yes, the dour ranger may be capable of even love, as the little confession from Catti-Brie seems to indicate. Die-hard Drizzt fans may not want to miss the moment he plants a wet kiss on Catti-Brie&rsquo;s lips, though whether she is aware of it is unclear.</p>

<p>As serious as the story seems, RA Salvatore&rsquo;s naming scheme may need a little more work. Many of the names are original, but some, like Wulfgar, Alustriel, Morkai, etc. come off as a little generic. Drizzt&rsquo;s name for his scimitar, &ldquo;Twinkle&rdquo;, hardly befits a deadly weapon. I hope his nickname for Guenhwyvar isn&rsquo;t &ldquo;Pussycat&rdquo;. My last complaint has to do with the &ldquo;battle&rdquo; for Mithral Hall. That&rsquo;s just it, there is no battle. I had looked forward to seeing the combined forces of barbarians, dwarves, and wizards rout the despised duergars. Instead, the author seems to have run out of his page quota and only devotes a few brief passages to the party&rsquo;s triumphant return to Mithral Hall. Somewhat disappointing, but I suppose by this time the book will already have fulfilled its purpose.</p>

<p>While this book doesn&rsquo;t quite measure up to Streams of Silver, congratulations for putting this series under your belt. Now you can join Drizzt Do'Urden in his next exciting adventure, be it in Menzoberranzan or Faerun. If you don&rsquo;t feel intrigued with Drizzt after having read this series, I&rsquo;m a bearded gnome.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted March 13, 2003 on Amazon.com</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Crystal Shard (Forgotten Realms: The Icewind Dale Trilogy, Book 1) by R. A. Salvatore]]></title>
    <link href="http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2011/09/07/the-crystal-shard-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-1-by-r-a-salvatore/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dinhyen.github.io/blog/2011/09/07/the-crystal-shard-forgotten-realms-the-icewind-dale-trilogy-book-1-by-r-a-salvatore</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="pull-left" title="The Crystal Shard" src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/52804626/images/The-Crystal-Shard-181x300.jpg" width="181" height="300" />The main problem with works that are inspired by or that borrow from RPG is predictability. After all, what adventure would be complete without a warrior, a rogue, and a sorcerer. Not to mention the party must include a gruff dwarf and a light-hearted, pleasure-loving halfling. The Crystal Shard has got all that and more, but it also brings to life an original in the form of Drizzt Do'Urden, who&rsquo;s undoubtedly one of the most well-known and beloved characters in fantasy. That may be the most enduring legacy of this fun if otherwise unremarkable series.</p>

<p>The story is set in the Icewind Dale, a barren, wind-swept region nestled in the armpit of the Spine of the World. Thanks to its remote location, Icewind Dale is largely ignored, until our present story that is, in the lores of the Forgotten Realms, that fabled realm of the vast Dungeons &amp; Dragons universe. Icewind Dale is home to Bruenor, a old, curmudgeonly dwarf (who&rsquo;s ever heard of a happy go lucky dwarf?), who fled here after the destruction of his ancestral home, and the halfing Regis, an epicurean who&rsquo;s on the run from some trouble in the south. Befriended to both is Drizzt, a drow-elf ranger on an self-imposed exile from the underground realms of his people. Highly principled and strongly disturbed by the evil and self-serving ways of the drow, he willingly makes his home on the surface world despite the fear and revulsion of almost everyone he comes across. Drizzt&rsquo;s background and emotional complexity makes him a deeper characters than one would expect from a series like this. Rounding out the group are Catti-Brie, a human girl adopted by Bruenor, and Wulfgar, a fierce barbarian warrior taken under Bruenor&rsquo;s tutelage. Trouble brews when Akar Kessell, a bumbling wizard&rsquo;s apprentice, stumbled into possession of Crenshinibon, an almost sentient crystal imbued with vast powers. Aided by the crystal, Kessell assembles a vast army of goblins, orcs and giants to invade Ten Towns and establish himself as the tyrant of Icewind Dale. Drizzt and company must rally the squabbling inhabitants of Ten Towns and gain the help of the hitherto hostile barbarian tribes if everyone is to have a chance.</p>

<p>As transparent as the plot may seem, there are memorable moments such as Drizzt&rsquo;s confrontation with the demon Erttu and Wulfgar&rsquo;s journey to the lair of the ice dragon. This was RA Salvatore&rsquo;s first major work and there are some rough edges here and there. The battle of Bryn Shander somehow lacks the fury and scale of a climactic clash (face it, few are going to be able to outdo the battles of Helm&rsquo;s Deep and the Pelennor Fields). Nevertheless, the author does an excellent job to bring excitement to one-on-one swashbuckling; one can almost envision the blur of Drizzt&rsquo;s dual scimitars or Wulfgar hammering everything into smithereens with mighty Aegis-Fang.</p>

<p>The Crystal Shard has something about each character. While I would have wished for less stereotypical portrayals and a little more depth, it&rsquo;s a satisfactory introduction and launches us immediately into the companions' even more exciting second adventure.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted March 14, 2003 on Amazon.com</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
