<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hiking on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://yentran.org/tags/hiking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hiking on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yentran.org/tags/hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Gorham Mountain</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-05-acadia-national-park-gorham-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-05-acadia-national-park-gorham-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike on Gorham Mountain Trail.
Because it&amp;rsquo;s the only national park in the northeastern US, I&amp;rsquo;ve visited Acadia National Park several times over the years. But I&amp;rsquo;m a bit mystified that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to hike it just once, and it was only last year. I think it is because I&amp;rsquo;ve come here in a large group, for which it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to plan a hike. Further, there are so many things to do that we&amp;rsquo;ve always managed to find other alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Mount Monadnock</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-11-hiking-mount-monadnock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-11-hiking-mount-monadnock/</guid>
      <description>As far as big mountain goes,[ Mount Monadnock](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Monadnock&amp;quot; targtet=&amp;quot;_blank) in the southwestern corner of New Hampshire is relatively close to Boston. Despite its proximity, we&amp;rsquo;ve never set foot on it. So we set out on a beautiful Saturday morning to redress this omission.
Monadnock&amp;rsquo;s claim to fame is its status as most hiked mountain in the US. Not so surprisingly, as soon as we arrived, the park ranger informed us that the parking lot was filled so that we&amp;rsquo;d have to park in the camping area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Mount Misery</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-06-hiking-mount-misery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-06-hiking-mount-misery/</guid>
      <description>We went for a short hike over the long Labor Day weekend. To get there we drove through very picturesque Lincoln Center. Note to self: come back here for a bike ride in the fall. The trail head is located at the back of the very unremarkable parking lot for the local commuter train station.
Despite its formidable and romantic name, Mount Misery is anything but. It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively small hill which barely rises above the tree line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn foliage 2010</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-23-foliage-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-23-foliage-2010/</guid>
      <description>In the autumn of 2010, a few friends and I spent a weekend in the White Mountains, New Hampshire and another in the Berkshires, Western Massachusetts. The former was a bit more adventurous. We went on a hike on North Moat Mountain and underestimated the terrain (or overestimated our ability). Even though we&amp;rsquo;re decent hikers and were appropriately equipped, 8-9 miles of strenuous hike coupled with a late start were our undoing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
