<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terry Goodkind on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://yentran.org/tags/terry-goodkind/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Terry Goodkind on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yentran.org/tags/terry-goodkind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Faith of the Fallen (Sword of Truth series, Book 6) by Terry Goodkind</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-book-review-faith-of-the-fallen-sword-of-truth-series-book-6-by-terry-goodkind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-book-review-faith-of-the-fallen-sword-of-truth-series-book-6-by-terry-goodkind/</guid>
      <description>Faith of the Fallen picks up where Soul of the Fire left off. It follows several characters while advancing the main storyline. The climax, which brings together major threads in the story, is done in the typical Goodkind fashion, action-filled and satisfying. On the flip side, with this and the previous installment, Goodkind seems to have departed from the usual sword- and sorcery-oriented storytelling. Sure, there are intense battles to whet our appetites, but the principal focus of the book was on the nature of human character and society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soul of the Fire (Sword of Truth series, Book 5) by Terry Goodkind</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-book-review-soul-of-the-fire-sword-of-truth-series-book-5-by-terry-goodkind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-book-review-soul-of-the-fire-sword-of-truth-series-book-5-by-terry-goodkind/</guid>
      <description>This book is perhaps a let-down from the enthralling Temple of the Winds. The surprising discoveries, the heart-pounding action of the previous volumes are missing here, even during the climax, and the main danger seems somehow diminished and unimportant. The storyline doesn&amp;rsquo;t concern much with magic; in fact the absence of it is the crux of the story. What we&amp;rsquo;ve got left has mostly to do with the world of ordinary, non-magic people (muggles?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temple of the Winds (Sword of Truth series, Book 4) by Terry Goodkind</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-book-review-temple-of-the-winds-sword-of-truth-series-book-4-by-terry-goodkind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-book-review-temple-of-the-winds-sword-of-truth-series-book-4-by-terry-goodkind/</guid>
      <description>I must admit I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very impressed when I started reading the 1st book of the series. In Wizard&amp;rsquo;s First Rule, Goodkind&amp;rsquo;s writing just didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to possess a certain sophistication and polish, and at times it had such a wooden quality that I found myself squirming. Now after having read through the 5th book of the series, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I&amp;rsquo;ve stuck around! As the tale progresses, so does the author&amp;rsquo;s mastery of his craft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pillars of Creation (Sword of Truth series, Book 7) by Terry Goodkind</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-book-review-the-pillars-of-creation-sword-of-truth-series-book-7-by-terry-goodkind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-book-review-the-pillars-of-creation-sword-of-truth-series-book-7-by-terry-goodkind/</guid>
      <description>Pillars of Creation follows the adventures of a young woman, Jennsen, illegitimate daughter of Darken Rahl, as she travels the world in search of escape and vengeance. She is aided by a spy of the Imperial Order who may be more than he appears to be. At the same time, Jennsen&amp;rsquo;s unique ability may mean the end of all life, if she and Richard don&amp;rsquo;t discover the truth in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizard&#39;s First Rule (Sword of Truth series, Book 1) by Terry Goodkind</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-06-book-review-wizards-first-rule-sword-of-truth-series-book-1-by-terry-goodkind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-06-book-review-wizards-first-rule-sword-of-truth-series-book-1-by-terry-goodkind/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for an enthralling fantasy epic, look no further than the Sword of Truth series. Though Wizard&amp;rsquo;s First Rule isn&amp;rsquo;t the best of the series, it&amp;rsquo;s a must-read because it sets the background for the rest of the series.
Richard Cypher, a simple woods guide from the land of Hartland, has a chance encounter with a mysterious woman and soon finds himself at the center of quest to prevent a magic box of vast power from falling into the hands of Darken Rahl, a &amp;ldquo;dark&amp;rdquo; wizard of with unimaginable power and unsurpassed cruelty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
