<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rant on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://yentran.org/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rant on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yentran.org/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sports I would watch</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2014-02-07-sports-i-would-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2014-02-07-sports-i-would-watch/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;if I had an unlimited amount of free time, bathroom breaks and no desire to have a life.
 Olympic men&amp;rsquo;s hockey Bruins hockey NHL hockey IIHF tournament hockey such as the World Juniors Top-flight European professional hockey (KHL, Swedish Elite League, Finnish Elite League) Olympic women&amp;rsquo;s hockey. It&amp;rsquo;s enjoyable but less exciting than the men&amp;rsquo;s game due to the lack of strong competition; basically it&amp;rsquo;s a 2-horse race between Canada and USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Bruins&#39; 2011 White House appearance</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-01-23-on-the-bruins-2011-white-house-appearance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-01-23-on-the-bruins-2011-white-house-appearance/</guid>
      <description>Today the Bruins appeared at the White House where President Obama greeted them and honored their accomplishments as 2011 Stanley Cup champions. Included in the group photo were Americans, Canadians, Czechs, a Slovak, a Finn, and a German. Notable in his absence was Bruins goalie Tim Thomas, Stanley Cup playoffs MVP, winner of multiple awards and the only American player who made significant contribution to the team&amp;rsquo;s Cup run. The details of Thomas&#39; absence are covered elsewhere, but it has become clear that it is politically motivated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 reasons why hockey is the best</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-21-why-hockey-is-the-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-06-21-why-hockey-is-the-best/</guid>
      <description>Would you expect any less from a die-hard hockey fan? So with a warning that this is going to be shamelessly biased, here goes.
 At the 2011 NHL All-Stars game, NY Islanders forward Michael Grabner won the Fastest Skater competition with a time of 14.238 seconds. The track length is about 550 ft. This translates to 38.6 ft or 12.9 yards/second. For comparison, let&amp;rsquo;s look at the fastest 40-yard dash for football players, who are speedsters in their own right.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
