<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>android on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://yentran.org/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in android on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yentran.org/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to not upgrade the Nexus 7 to Lollipop</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2015-02-16-how-to-not-upgrade-the-nexus-7-to-lollipop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2015-02-16-how-to-not-upgrade-the-nexus-7-to-lollipop/</guid>
      <description>I have a first-generation Nexus 7 tablet made by Asus which ran KitKat 4.4. When the OTA Lollipop update became available, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to install it. The latest and greatest Android running on Google hardware seemed to be a match made in heaven; it would be better, prettier and faster, right? As you can probably guess from the title of this post, the answer was a resounding no. Everything became sluggish, swipes would only registered after a couple of seconds, random things popped open and close.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading the HTC Aria with Android Gingerbread and CyanogenMod</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-12-31-installing-cyanogenmod-on-the-htc-aria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-12-31-installing-cyanogenmod-on-the-htc-aria/</guid>
      <description>I have an HTC Aria which runs now-ancient Android 2.1. This phone is far from being the latest and greatest, to put it mildly, but I like its small form factor. After putting up with it for a year, I have had enough and decided to upgrade it to Gingerbread. This is how I did it. As this is my first attempt, no doubt there are different and better ways to do things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
