<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hiking on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://yentran.org/categories/hiking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hiking on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yentran.org/categories/hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu, Peru (Day 5, 6)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-31-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-31-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike to Intipunku, the Inca Bridge and down to Aguas Calientes (the GPS track recorded by the logger is a little out of sync with Google Map, but you get the idea).
Had Machu Picchu been built in Cusco, it would have been just as spectacular. But being perched on a remote mountaintop, invisible from below, covered by swirling mists, and (when &amp;ldquo;discovered&amp;rdquo; by Hiram Bingham) overrun by the jungle gives it an unmatched mystique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Písac, Peru (Day 4)</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-19-pisac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-19-pisac/</guid>
      <description>Map of our walking route of Písac.
Most people know about Cusco and Machu Picchu, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much more. Stretched between the two is the valley formed by the Urubamba (or Vilcanota) river, the so-called Sacred Valley of the Incas. Inca settlements, temples and monuments are found through the valley and towns such as Písac and Ollantaytambo are home to spectacular ruins. Those who are up for an outdoor experience can even take the Inca trail, the ancient highway to Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Dorr Mountain</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-dorr-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-dorr-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Map of our round-trip hike to Dorr Mountain from Sieur de Monts.
Dorr Mountain is the second highest peak on Mount Desert Island, behind only Cadillac Mountain. It&amp;rsquo;s named after George Dorr, who&amp;rsquo;s affectionately known as the father of Acadia National Park. There are multiple paths to the summit. We chose to start from Sieur de Monts spring.
There are a couple of trails crisscrossing the area. The most obvious is Emery Path, which begins right behind the small visitors&#39; center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Great Head Trail</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-great-head-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-great-head-trail/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike on the Great Head Trail.
Great Head sticks out like a polyp from the southwest corner of Mount Desert Island. Its exposed location means that there are great views up and down the entire length of the island. Unfortunately its proximity and easy access to the ever popular Sand Beach also means that the likelihood of running into flip-flop-wearing, towel-toting, rubbernecking tourists who have never seen the inside of a trailhead is quite high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Jesup Path</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-jesup-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-jesup-path/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike on Jesup Path.
Along with [Emery Path](http://www.yentran.org/blog/2012/07/acadia-national-park-dorr-mountain/&amp;quot; title=&amp;ldquo;Acadia National Park: Dorr Mountain), Jesup Path is another trail which can be found at the Sieur de Monts spring area. Straight and level, it&amp;rsquo;s hardly a challenging hike. Its claim to fame, I think, is an eternity of boardwalk amid a picturesque forest of birch trees and tall grass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: The Bubbles</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-08-acadia-national-park-the-bubbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-08-acadia-national-park-the-bubbles/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike on the North and South Bubble Mountains
When seen from a distance, it&amp;rsquo;s immediately obvious why the Bubbles are so named, though I&amp;rsquo;m sure you can think of more colorful analogies. Located just a short distance from the Park Loop Road and the popular Jordan Pond, they&amp;rsquo;re some of the most accessible climbs in the park. Both offer splendid views of Jordan Pond and, in the distance, the islands off the southern coast of Mount Desert Island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Gorham Mountain</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-05-acadia-national-park-gorham-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-05-acadia-national-park-gorham-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike on Gorham Mountain Trail.
Because it&amp;rsquo;s the only national park in the northeastern US, I&amp;rsquo;ve visited Acadia National Park several times over the years. But I&amp;rsquo;m a bit mystified that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to hike it just once, and it was only last year. I think it is because I&amp;rsquo;ve come here in a large group, for which it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to plan a hike. Further, there are so many things to do that we&amp;rsquo;ve always managed to find other alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Mount Monadnock</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-09-11-hiking-mount-monadnock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-09-11-hiking-mount-monadnock/</guid>
      <description>As far as big mountain goes,[ Mount Monadnock](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Monadnock&amp;quot; targtet=&amp;quot;_blank) in the southwestern corner of New Hampshire is relatively close to Boston. Despite its proximity, we&amp;rsquo;ve never set foot on it. So we set out on a beautiful Saturday morning to redress this omission.
Monadnock&amp;rsquo;s claim to fame is its status as most hiked mountain in the US. Not so surprisingly, as soon as we arrived, the park ranger informed us that the parking lot was filled so that we&amp;rsquo;d have to park in the camping area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Mount Misery</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-09-06-hiking-mount-misery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-09-06-hiking-mount-misery/</guid>
      <description>We went for a short hike over the long Labor Day weekend. To get there we drove through very picturesque Lincoln Center. Note to self: come back here for a bike ride in the fall. The trail head is located at the back of the very unremarkable parking lot for the local commuter train station.
Despite its formidable and romantic name, Mount Misery is anything but. It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively small hill which barely rises above the tree line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
