<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>acadia national park on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://yentran.org/tags/acadia-national-park/</link>
    <description>Recent content in acadia national park on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yentran.org/tags/acadia-national-park/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Dorr Mountain</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-dorr-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-dorr-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Map of our round-trip hike to Dorr Mountain from Sieur de Monts.
Dorr Mountain is the second highest peak on Mount Desert Island, behind only Cadillac Mountain. It&amp;rsquo;s named after George Dorr, who&amp;rsquo;s affectionately known as the father of Acadia National Park. There are multiple paths to the summit. We chose to start from Sieur de Monts spring.
There are a couple of trails crisscrossing the area. The most obvious is Emery Path, which begins right behind the small visitors&#39; center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Great Head Trail</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-great-head-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-great-head-trail/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike on the Great Head Trail.
Great Head sticks out like a polyp from the southwest corner of Mount Desert Island. Its exposed location means that there are great views up and down the entire length of the island. Unfortunately its proximity and easy access to the ever popular Sand Beach also means that the likelihood of running into flip-flop-wearing, towel-toting, rubbernecking tourists who have never seen the inside of a trailhead is quite high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Jesup Path</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-jesup-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-10-acadia-national-park-jesup-path/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike on Jesup Path.
Along with [Emery Path](http://www.yentran.org/blog/2012/07/acadia-national-park-dorr-mountain/&amp;quot; title=&amp;ldquo;Acadia National Park: Dorr Mountain), Jesup Path is another trail which can be found at the Sieur de Monts spring area. Straight and level, it&amp;rsquo;s hardly a challenging hike. Its claim to fame, I think, is an eternity of boardwalk amid a picturesque forest of birch trees and tall grass.
                                     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Cadillac Mountain</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-08-acadia-national-park-cadillac-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-08-acadia-national-park-cadillac-mountain/</guid>
      <description>The tallest peak in Acadia and the first place in the continental US to see the morning light, Cadillac Mountain is also the most accessible &amp;ndash; you can just drive there. Nevertheless, its popularity doesn&amp;rsquo;t detract from its appeal. Unfortunately we couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it here early enough for sunrise, being worn out from hiking every day. So we had to settle for the &amp;ldquo;other golden hour&amp;rdquo;. Fortunately with a storm brewing in the distance all afternoon, we were treated to a beautiful sunset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: The Bubbles</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-08-acadia-national-park-the-bubbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-08-acadia-national-park-the-bubbles/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike on the North and South Bubble Mountains
When seen from a distance, it&amp;rsquo;s immediately obvious why the Bubbles are so named, though I&amp;rsquo;m sure you can think of more colorful analogies. Located just a short distance from the Park Loop Road and the popular Jordan Pond, they&amp;rsquo;re some of the most accessible climbs in the park. Both offer splendid views of Jordan Pond and, in the distance, the islands off the southern coast of Mount Desert Island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Biking the carriage roads</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-05-acadia-national-park-biking-the-carriage-roads/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-05-acadia-national-park-biking-the-carriage-roads/</guid>
      <description>Another unique feature of Acadia is the extensive system of carriage roads. Built in the first half of the 20th century by the Rockefeller family for use by horses and carriages, these roads traverse Mount Desert Island and offer unparalleled access to the its interior. These are possibly the most scenic bike paths anywhere. Due to its length of more than 45 miles, the carriage roads are best experienced on a bicycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia National Park: Gorham Mountain</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-05-acadia-national-park-gorham-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2012-07-05-acadia-national-park-gorham-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike on Gorham Mountain Trail.
Because it&amp;rsquo;s the only national park in the northeastern US, I&amp;rsquo;ve visited Acadia National Park several times over the years. But I&amp;rsquo;m a bit mystified that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to hike it just once, and it was only last year. I think it is because I&amp;rsquo;ve come here in a large group, for which it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to plan a hike. Further, there are so many things to do that we&amp;rsquo;ve always managed to find other alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
