<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>city on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://yentran.org/categories/city/</link>
    <description>Recent content in city on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yentran.org/categories/city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paris 1999</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-08-09-paris-flashback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-08-09-paris-flashback/</guid>
      <description>I took a trip outside of the US for the first time in 1999. My sister and I got to spend a week in Paris, then took a train to the Netherlands where we toured the country for another week with a friend. Traveling so far from home by ourselves was exciting enough, and being in the most beautiful and metropolitan city in the world turned it into an unforgettable experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cusco, Peru (Day 3, 4, 6)</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-17-cusco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-17-cusco/</guid>
      <description>We arrived at airport with just 1 hour to spare. I am quite impressed with LAN Chile Airline. Plenty of professional bilingual staff are available to assist passengers at automated check-in kiosks. Oh and they&amp;rsquo;re all attractive young women. In other parts of the world some old traditions still persist. Our flight to Cusco was short, about 1h. Our Peruvian fellow passenger was nice enough to stick the my GPS receiver behind the window shade so that we get a GPS trace of the flight path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lima, Peru (Day 1 &amp; 2)</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-16-lima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-16-lima/</guid>
      <description>Our Peru adventure didn&amp;rsquo;t start out well. Our flight from Boston was delayed for 90 min and managed to land in Newark 5 minutes after the connection had already left. We were rerouted to Miami and put on a flight to Lima that arrived at 4:30 in the morning. The streets were mostly devoid of traffic though surprisingly some street sweepers were out working. Leaving the airport we scurried through a warren of narrow streets not unlike San Jose, Costa Rica, but soon things opened up when we got on the highway that runs along the ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hub on Wheels 2010</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-07-10-hub-on-wheels-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-07-10-hub-on-wheels-2010/</guid>
      <description>Every September since 2005, the city of Boston has held a charity bike ride to benefit of one of its educational programs. The event is called Hub on Wheels, a clever pun based on Boston&amp;rsquo;s modest nickname for itself, the Hub of the Universe. For the majority of riders, it would be the only time of the year that they get an intimate view of some of Boston&amp;rsquo;s lesser-known neighborhoods. There are 3 available courses, 10-, 30- and 50-mile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t trip and fall: The Chihuly exhibit</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-21-dont-trip-and-fall-the-chihuly-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-21-dont-trip-and-fall-the-chihuly-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday, we visited the Chihuly exhibit at the MFA. Like most people, I strained to find familiar words to describe something unfamiliar (during those moments when my mind wasn&amp;rsquo;t occupied with playing over and over the disastrous scenario of inadvertently knocking something down). Here are some of the ones I came up with. But sometimes, you just have to admit that there isn&amp;rsquo;t a word.
wavy pearlescent translucent veiny swirling fantastic alien bulbous metallic coppery rainbow writhing ghostly shimmering glowing sheet-like variegated striped spotted medusa crystalline fortress-of-solitude brilliant kaleidoscopic vivid silkworms frog-toes tentacled calamari tubular spiky light-saber agave</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Bruins Stanley Cup Parade</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</guid>
      <description>Boston&amp;rsquo;s first Stanley Cup parade in 39 years was going to take place on Saturday, June 18, three days after the team celebrated on the ice in Vancouver. It was as definitive a &amp;ldquo;clear your calendar&amp;rdquo;-type event as it will ever be. On the morning of C-day, we got up early, loaded up with a hearty breakfast, filled the caffeine meter, and made sure we went to the bathroom before heading down to the T.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
