<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Suzuki on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://yentran.org/tags/suzuki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Suzuki on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yentran.org/tags/suzuki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Costa Rica Day 4 (Friday) - Arenal to Monteverde</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-30-costa-rica-day-4-friday-arenal-to-monteverde/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-30-costa-rica-day-4-friday-arenal-to-monteverde/</guid>
      <description>Breakfast included blackberry and papaya juice. I love this place! We bid farewell to our avian and reptilian friends. There was some commotion on the other side of the dining hall. Our waiter, like other Ticos always eager to point out cool things to us gringos, motioned us to come over. There was a caiman sunning himself just on the other side of the river. He also gave thumbs up to Monteverde&amp;rsquo;s ranarium and butterfly garden; even though he had never been to Monteverde, he learned about them from the hotel&amp;rsquo;s tour leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Costa Rica Day 1 (Tuesday) - San Jose</title>
      <link>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-29-costa-rica-day-1-san-jose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yentran.org/post/2011-05-29-costa-rica-day-1-san-jose/</guid>
      <description>I just came back from a second visit to Costa Rica, the first being 2 years ago. This trip was quite spontaneous, after plans to catch a friend during her last semester in Venice fell through.
After not being quite prepared for the torrential tropical downpours or having a decent camera last time, I resolved that things would be different this time. Checklist:
 guide book (2008 edition), Spanish phrasebook (unfortunately meant for Spain/Portugal as I lent someone the Costa Rica edition), camera + telephoto lens + tripod for waterfalls shots, Bose noise-canceling headphone, book club read (Blue Highway by William Least Heat-Moon), pair of binoculars, bug repellent, waterproof jacket, hiking boots, quick-drying pants and shirts, and ATM card (I had already called ahead to notify the bank that I would be using my credit and debit card abroad).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
