<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Boston Bruins on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://yentran.org/tags/boston-bruins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Boston Bruins on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yentran.org/tags/boston-bruins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who are the 2011 Bruins?</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-23-who-are-the-bruins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-23-who-are-the-bruins/</guid>
      <description>Defensemen #33 Zdeno Chara - Tallest man in hockey history and probably using the longest stick and wearing the largest skates as well. With his monstrous wingspan he can easily cover his half of the ice. Very nice guy off the ice, but a big (and tall) bogeyman on it.
#44 Dennis Seidenberg - Rugged German-born defenseman. Blocks a ton of shot. Possesses outstanding balance and is very strong on his skates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Bruins Stanley Cup Parade</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-18-stanley-cup-parade/</guid>
      <description>Boston&amp;rsquo;s first Stanley Cup parade in 39 years was going to take place on Saturday, June 18, three days after the team celebrated on the ice in Vancouver. It was as definitive a &amp;ldquo;clear your calendar&amp;rdquo;-type event as it will ever be. On the morning of C-day, we got up early, loaded up with a hearty breakfast, filled the caffeine meter, and made sure we went to the bathroom before heading down to the T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We won the Cup!</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-15-we-won-the-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-15-we-won-the-cup/</guid>
      <description>Zdeno Chara grabbed hold of the Cup, reverently brought it to his lips, then raised it above his head, repeating a ritual performed by all previous Cup-winning captains. The only difference was that it had not been done by someone wearing the spoked-B since Nixon was President. The events of this night surely sent Bruins fans everywhere into a delirium. For the entire time that the Bruins celebrated on the ice, I had a stupidly wide grin on my face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We want the Cup!</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-14-we-want-the-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-14-we-want-the-cup/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the eve before the biggest game in my history as a Bruins fan. I&amp;rsquo;m so nervous I&amp;rsquo;m going to have problem going to sleep. I had known about hockey quite early on since Las Vegas had a minor-league team, the now-defunct Las Vegas Thunder, and a friend was a big fan. Despite knowing so little about the game, I was hooked immediately when I came to Boston in the mid-90s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The man they call Bobby</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-09-the-man-they-call-bobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-06-09-the-man-they-call-bobby/</guid>
      <description>TD Bank Garden, Boston on June 8, around 19:00. It was moments before Game 4 of the Stanley Cup finals between the Boston Bruins and the Vancouver Canucks. In the darkened arena, packed to the rafters with almost 18000 screaming fans, the lone spotlight descended on an area in the stands. Momentarily, a middle-aged man clad in a vintage Bruins jersey stepped into the light. The crowd erupted. It was none other than the legendary Bobby Orr, the man universally regarded as the finest defenseman in the history of hockey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
