<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruins on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://yentran.org/tags/ruins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ruins on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yentran.org/tags/ruins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ollantaytambo, Peru (Day 6)</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-08-07-ollantaytambo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-08-07-ollantaytambo/</guid>
      <description>On our last day in Peru, our flight from Cusco wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be until 15h30. Until then we could either wander around Cusco or use our Boleto Turístico to explore the other ruins on the outskirts of Cusco (Puca Pucara, Q&amp;rsquo;enqo and Tambomachay). However, we had heard really good things about Ollantaytambo. As it turned out, when we returned from Machu Picchu the night before, Lima Tours sent a driver to pick us up at Ollantaytambo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu, Peru (Day 5, 6)</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-31-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-31-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Map of our hike to Intipunku, the Inca Bridge and down to Aguas Calientes (the GPS track recorded by the logger is a little out of sync with Google Map, but you get the idea).
Had Machu Picchu been built in Cusco, it would have been just as spectacular. But being perched on a remote mountaintop, invisible from below, covered by swirling mists, and (when &amp;ldquo;discovered&amp;rdquo; by Hiram Bingham) overrun by the jungle gives it an unmatched mystique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sacsayhuamán, Peru (Day 4)</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-24-sacsayhuaman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-24-sacsayhuaman/</guid>
      <description>The largest Inca complex in Cusco is Sacsayhuamán, a walled fortress which stands on a hill overlooking the city. It&amp;rsquo;s believed that the Incas built the city of Cusco in the shape of a jaguar, with Sacsayhuamán representing the head (and the most formidable part) of the jaguar. It may be hard to see it now, as the city has undergone dramatic changes in the intervening centuries. But it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see how the jagged outline of the walls bears remarkable resemblance to rows of teeth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Písac, Peru (Day 4)</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-19-pisac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-19-pisac/</guid>
      <description>Map of our walking route of Písac.
Most people know about Cusco and Machu Picchu, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much more. Stretched between the two is the valley formed by the Urubamba (or Vilcanota) river, the so-called Sacred Valley of the Incas. Inca settlements, temples and monuments are found through the valley and towns such as Písac and Ollantaytambo are home to spectacular ruins. Those who are up for an outdoor experience can even take the Inca trail, the ancient highway to Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cusco, Peru (Day 3, 4, 6)</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-17-cusco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2012-07-17-cusco/</guid>
      <description>We arrived at airport with just 1 hour to spare. I am quite impressed with LAN Chile Airline. Plenty of professional bilingual staff are available to assist passengers at automated check-in kiosks. Oh and they&amp;rsquo;re all attractive young women. In other parts of the world some old traditions still persist. Our flight to Cusco was short, about 1h. Our Peruvian fellow passenger was nice enough to stick the my GPS receiver behind the window shade so that we get a GPS trace of the flight path.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
