<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tracy Hickman on Yen&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://yentran.org/tags/tracy-hickman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tracy Hickman on Yen&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yentran.org/tags/tracy-hickman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dragons of Autumn Twilight (Dragonlance Chronicles, Volume I) by Margaret Weis &amp; Tracy Hickman</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-dragons-of-autumn-twilight-dragonlance-chronicles-volume-i-by-margaret-weis-tracy-hickman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-dragons-of-autumn-twilight-dragonlance-chronicles-volume-i-by-margaret-weis-tracy-hickman/</guid>
      <description>The DragonLance saga is one of the most prolific in fantasy, with scores of prequels and sequels and offshoots and imitators. The DragonLance Chronicles is the series that started it all. To call it anything less than a classic would be sacrilegious. Deeply rooted in the mythos of Tolkien and heavily influenced by the rules and mechanics of the RPG world, the DragonLance Chronicles manages to create a vast high-fantasy universe with few equals then or since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragons of Spring Dawning (Dragonlance Chronicles, Book 3) by Margaret Weis &amp; Tracy Hickman</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-dragons-of-spring-dawning-dragonlance-chronicles-book-3-by-margaret-weis-tracy-hickman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-dragons-of-spring-dawning-dragonlance-chronicles-book-3-by-margaret-weis-tracy-hickman/</guid>
      <description>After the setback at the end of book two, hope finally dawns on Krynn. For the rediscovered dragonlances and the return of the good metallic dragons are finally turning the tide of fortunes against the forces of darkness in the War of the Lance. In the north, under the leadership of a new general, none other than one of our familiar companions, victories follow victories, cities are retaken, enemy commanders are captured, and for a time, evil seems to be on the verge of defeat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragons of Winter Night (Dragonlance Chronicles, Volume II) by Margaret Weis &amp; Tracy Hickman</title>
      <link>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-dragons-of-winter-night-dragonlance-chronicles-volume-ii-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yentran.org/post/source/2011-09-07-dragons-of-winter-night-dragonlance-chronicles-volume-ii-by/</guid>
      <description>The middle child of a trilogy has the most tenuous position. After all, the novelty may have worn off after the first installment and the big ending doesn&amp;rsquo;t come until the next. Many are relegated to simply serve as a bridge between the first and third installment. Dragons of Winter Night defies stereotypes with its gripping storyline filled with many tense sequences and surprising revelations. True to the title, the mood is considerably darker than in the first book, ending with the heroic sacrifice of one of the main characters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
